{"T4B11": {"question": "Which of the following describes the common meaning of the term \"repeater offset\"?", "ans_a": "A. The distance between the repeater\u2019s transmit and receive antennas", "ans_d": "D. Matching the antenna impedance to the feed line impedance", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The difference between the repeater\u2019s transmit and receive frequencies", "ans_b": "B. The time delay before the repeater timer resets"}, "T1F02": {"question": "When using tactical identifiers such as \u201cRace Headquarters\u201d during a community service net operation, how often must your station transmit the station\u2019s FCC-assigned call sign? ", "ans_a": "A. Never, the tactical call is sufficient", "ans_d": "D. At the end of every transmission", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. At the end of each communication and every ten minutes during a communication", "ans_b": "B. Once during every hour"}, "T5D04": {"question": "What is the resistance of a circuit in which a current of 3 amperes flows through a resistor connected to 90 volts?", "ans_a": "A. 3 ohms", "ans_d": "D. 270 ohms", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 93 ohms", "ans_b": "B. 30 ohms"}, "T7A06": {"question": "What device takes the output of a low-powered 28 MHz SSB exciter and produces a 222 MHz output signal?", "ans_a": "A. High-pass filter", "ans_d": "D. Phase converter", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Transverter", "ans_b": "B. Low-pass filter"}, "T7B10": {"question": "What might be the problem if you receive a report that your audio signal through the repeater is distorted or unintelligible?", "ans_a": "A. Your transmitter may be slightly off frequency", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. You could be in a bad location", "ans_b": "B. Your batteries may be running low"}, "T6D04": {"question": "Which of the following can be used to display signal strength on a numeric scale?", "ans_a": "A. Potentiometer", "ans_d": "D. Relay", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Meter", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T2A04": {"question": "What is an appropriate way to call another station on a repeater if you know the other station's call sign?", "ans_a": "A. Say break, break then say the station's call sign", "ans_d": "D. Wait for the station to call CQ then answer it", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Say CQ three times then the other station's call sign", "ans_b": "B. Say the station's call sign then identify with your call sign"}, "T5C11": {"question": "How many amperes are flowing in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the load is 120 watts?", "ans_a": "A. 0.1 amperes", "ans_d": "D. 132 amperes", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 12 amperes", "ans_b": "B. 10 amperes"}, "T1B07": {"question": "What amateur band are you using if you are transmitting on 223.50 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. 15 meter band", "ans_d": "D. 1.25 meter band", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 2 meter band", "ans_b": "B. 10 meter band"}, "T6B05": {"question": "Which of the following electronic components can amplify signals?", "ans_a": "A. Transistor", "ans_d": "D. Multi-cell battery", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Electrolytic capacitor", "ans_b": "B. Variable resistor"}, "T6B11": {"question": "What at are the three electrodes of a field effect transistor?", "ans_a": "A. Emitter, base, and collector", "ans_d": "D. Cathode, gate, and anode", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Cathode, grid, and plate", "ans_b": "B. Source, gate, and drain"}, "T6D02": {"question": "What best describes a relay?", "ans_a": "A. A switch controlled by an electromagnet", "ans_d": "D. A pass transistor", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. An optical sensor", "ans_b": "B. A current controlled amplifier"}, "T1B11": {"question": "What emission modes are permitted in the mode-restricted sub-bands at 50.0 to 50.1 MHz and 144.0 to 144.1 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. CW only", "ans_d": "D. CW and SSB", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. SSB only", "ans_b": "B. CW and RTTY"}, "T8A09": {"question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a VHF repeater FM phone signal?", "ans_a": "A. Less than 500 Hz ", "ans_d": "D. Between 50 and 125 kHz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Between 10 and 15 kHz", "ans_b": "B. About 150 kHz"}, "T7C12": {"question": "Which of the following is a common use of coaxial cable?", "ans_a": "A. Carrying dc power from a vehicle battery to a mobile radio", "ans_d": "D. Connecting data signals from a TNC to a computer", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Securing masts, tubing, and other cylindrical objects on towers", "ans_b": "B. Carrying RF signals between a radio and antenna"}, "T1F04": {"question": "Which of the following is an acceptable language to use for station identification when operating in a phone sub-band?", "ans_a": "A. Any language recognized by the United Nations", "ans_d": "D. English, French, or Spanish", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The English language", "ans_b": "B. Any language recognized by the ITU"}, "T8D09": {"question": "What code is used when sending CW in the amateur bands?", "ans_a": "A. Baudot", "ans_d": "D. Gray", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. International Morse", "ans_b": "B. Hamming"}, "T7A09": {"question": "Which of the following devices is most useful for VHF weak-signal communication?", "ans_a": "A. A quarter-wave vertical antenna", "ans_d": "D. A mobile VHF FM transceiver", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. An omni-directional antenna", "ans_b": "B. A multi-mode VHF transceiver"}, "T1A11": {"question": "When is willful interference to other amateur radio stations permitted?", "ans_a": "A. Only if the station being interfered with is expressing extreme religious or political views ", "ans_d": "D. At any time, amateurs are not protected from willful interference", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Only during a contest", "ans_b": "B. At no time "}, "T9A07": {"question": "What is a good reason not to use a \u201crubber duck\u201d antenna inside your car?", "ans_a": "A. Signals can be significantly weaker than when it is outside of the vehicle", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The SWR might decrease, decreasing the signal strength", "ans_b": "B. It might cause your radio to overheat"}, "T2C07": {"question": "Which of the following is an accepted practice for an amateur operator who has checked into an emergency traffic net?", "ans_a": "A. Provided that the frequency is quiet, announce the station call sign and location every 5 minutes", "ans_d": "D. All of the choices are correct ", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Remain on frequency without transmitting until asked to do so by the net control station", "ans_b": "B. Move 5 kHz away from the net's frequency and use high power to ask other hams to keep clear of the net frequency"}, "T7B04": {"question": "Which of the following is a way to reduce or eliminate interference by an amateur transmitter to a nearby telephone?", "ans_a": "A. Put a filter on the amateur transmitter", "ans_d": "D. Put a RF filter on the telephone", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Reduce the SWR on the transmitter transmission line", "ans_b": "B. Reduce the microphone gain"}, "T8D04": {"question": "What type of transmission is indicated by the term NTSC?", "ans_a": "A. A Normal Transmission mode in Static Circuit", "ans_d": "D. A frame compression scheme for TV signals", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. An analog fast scan color TV signal", "ans_b": "B. A special mode for earth satellite uplink"}, "T1E06": {"question": "Under what type of control do APRS network digipeaters operate?", "ans_a": "A. Automatic", "ans_d": "D. Manual", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Local", "ans_b": "B. Remote"}, "T1B05": {"question": "Which 70 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class license holder operating in ITU Region 2?", "ans_a": "A. 53.350 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 222.520 MHz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 443.350 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 146.520 MHz"}, "T0C06": {"question": "Which of the following is an acceptable method to determine that your station complies with FCC RF exposure regulations?", "ans_a": "A. By calculation based on FCC OET Bulletin 65", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. By measurement of field strength using calibrated equipment", "ans_b": "B. By calculation based on computer modeling"}, "T2C04": {"question": "What do RACES and ARES have in common?", "ans_a": "A. They represent the two largest ham clubs in the United States", "ans_d": "D. Both organizations may provide communications during emergencies", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Neither may handle emergency traffic supporting public service agencies", "ans_b": "B. Both organizations broadcast road and weather information"}, "T6A10": {"question": "Which of the following battery types is rechargeable?", "ans_a": "A. Nickel-metal hydride", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Lead-acid gel-cell", "ans_b": "B. Lithium-ion"}, "T7B02": {"question": "What would cause a broadcast AM or FM radio to receive an amateur radio transmission unintentionally?", "ans_a": "A. The receiver is unable to reject strong signals outside the AM or FM band", "ans_d": "D. The deviation of an FM transmitter is set too low", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The audio amplifier of the transmitter is overloaded", "ans_b": "B. The microphone gain of the transmitter is turned up too high"}, "T2A11": {"question": "Which of the following is an FCC rule regarding power levels used in the amateur bands, under normal, non-distress circumstances?", "ans_a": "A. There is no limit to power as long as there is no interference with other services", "ans_d": "D. While not exceeding the maximum power permitted on a given band, use the minimum power necessary to carry out the desired communication", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Up to 1500 watts PEP may be used on any amateur frequency without restriction", "ans_b": "B. No more than 200 watts PEP may be used "}, "T1E09": {"question": "What type of control is being used when the control operator is at the control point?", "ans_a": "A. Radio control", "ans_d": "D. Local control", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Automatic control", "ans_b": "B. Unattended control"}, "T1C01": {"question": "Which type of call sign has a single letter in both its prefix and suffix?", "ans_a": "A. Vanity", "ans_d": "D. In-memoriam", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Special event", "ans_b": "B. Sequential"}, "T8C07": {"question": "What is the maximum power allowed when transmitting telecommand signals to radio controlled models?", "ans_a": "A. 500 milliwatts", "ans_d": "D. 1500 watts", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 25 watts", "ans_b": "B. 1 watt"}, "T6A02": {"question": "What type of component is often used as an adjustable volume control?", "ans_a": "A. Fixed resistor", "ans_d": "D. Transformer", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Potentiometer", "ans_b": "B. Power resistor"}, "T8B07": {"question": "With regard to satellite communications, what is Doppler shift?", "ans_a": "A. A change in the satellite orbit", "ans_d": "D. A special digital communications mode for some satellites", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. An observed change in signal frequency caused by relative motion between the satellite and the earth station", "ans_b": "B. A mode where the satellite receives signals on one band and transmits on another"}, "T5B06": {"question": "If an ammeter calibrated in amperes is used to measure a 3000-milliampere current, what reading would it show?", "ans_a": "A. 0.003 amperes", "ans_d": "D. 3,000,000 amperes", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 3 amperes", "ans_b": "B. 0.3 amperes"}, "T0B12": {"question": "Which of the following is good practice when installing ground wires on a tower for lightning protection?", "ans_a": "A. Put a loop in the ground connection to prevent water damage to the ground system", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Ensure that connections are short and direct", "ans_b": "B. Make sure that all bends in the ground wires are clean, right angle bends"}, "T5D10": {"question": "What is the voltage across a 2-ohm resistor if a current of 0.5 amperes flows through it?", "ans_a": "A. 1 volt", "ans_d": "D. 1.5 volts", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 2.5 volts", "ans_b": "B. 0.25 volts"}, "T8A04": {"question": "Which type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF and UHF voice repeaters?", "ans_a": "A. AM", "ans_d": "D. FM", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. PSK", "ans_b": "B. SSB"}, "T5A10": {"question": "Which term describes the rate at which electrical energy is used?", "ans_a": "A. Resistance", "ans_d": "D. Voltage", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Power", "ans_b": "B. Current"}, "T2C09": {"question": "Are amateur station control operators ever permitted to operate outside the frequency privileges of their license class?", "ans_a": "A. No", "ans_d": "D. Yes, but only if necessary in situations involving the immediate safety of human life or protection of property", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Yes, but only when part of a RACES emergency plan", "ans_b": "B. Yes, but only when part of a FEMA emergency plan"}, "T2C06": {"question": "Which of the following is an accepted practice to get the immediate attention of a net control station when reporting an emergency?", "ans_a": "A. Repeat the words SOS three times followed by the call sign of the reporting station", "ans_d": "D. Play a pre-recorded emergency alert tone followed by your call sign", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Begin your transmission by saying \"Priority\" or \"Emergency\" followed by your call sign", "ans_b": "B. Press the push-to-talk button three times"}, "T4B03": {"question": "What is the purpose of the squelch control on a transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. To set the highest level of volume desired", "ans_d": "D. To mute receiver output noise when no signal is being received", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. To adjust the automatic gain control", "ans_b": "B. To set the transmitter power level"}, "T8C05": {"question": "What is a grid locator?", "ans_a": "A. A letter-number designator assigned to a geographic location", "ans_d": "D. An instrument for radio direction finding", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. An instrument for neutralizing a final amplifier", "ans_b": "B. A letter-number designator assigned to an azimuth and elevation"}, "T6C04": {"question": "What is component 3 in figure T1?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Ground symbol", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Lamp", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T3A06": {"question": "What term is commonly used to describe the rapid fluttering sound sometimes heard from mobile stations that are moving while transmitting?", "ans_a": "A. Flip-flopping", "ans_d": "D. Pulsing", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Frequency shifting", "ans_b": "B. Picket fencing"}, "T1C14": {"question": "Who may select a vanity call sign for a club station?", "ans_a": "A. Any Extra Class member of the club", "ans_d": "D. Only the person named as trustee on the club station license grant", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Any officer of the club", "ans_b": "B. Any member of the club"}, "T9B05": {"question": "What generally happens as the frequency of a signal passing through coaxial cable is increased?", "ans_a": "A. The apparent SWR increases", "ans_d": "D. The loss increases", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The characteristic impedance increases", "ans_b": "B. The reflected power increases"}, "T7A07": {"question": "What is meant by term \u201cPTT\u201d?", "ans_a": "A. Pre-transmission tuning to reduce transmitter harmonic emission", "ans_d": "D. The push to talk function which switches between receive and transmit", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A primary transformer tuner use to match antennas", "ans_b": "B. Precise tone transmissions used to limit repeater access to only certain signals"}, "T1A14": {"question": "What must you do if you are operating on the 23 cm band and learn that you are interfering with a radiolocation station outside the United States?", "ans_a": "A. Stop operating or take steps to eliminate the harmful interference", "ans_d": "D. Change to CW mode, because this would not likely cause interference", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Establish contact with the radiolocation station and ask them to change frequency", "ans_b": "B. Nothing, because this band is allocated exclusively to the amateur service"}, "T5C05": {"question": "What is the unit of frequency?", "ans_a": "A. Hertz", "ans_d": "D. Tesla", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Farad", "ans_b": "B. Henry"}, "T7A03": {"question": "Which of the following is used to convert a radio signal from one frequency to another?", "ans_a": "A. Phase splitter", "ans_d": "D. Amplifier", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Inverter", "ans_b": "B. Mixer"}, "T5A03": {"question": "What is the name for the flow of electrons in an electric circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Voltage", "ans_d": "D. Current ", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Capacitance", "ans_b": "B. Resistance"}, "T5B12": {"question": "Which of the following frequencies is equal to 28,400 kHz?", "ans_a": "A. 28.400 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 28.400 kHz", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 284.00 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 2.800 MHz"}, "T4A01": {"question": "Which of the following is true concerning the microphone connectors on amateur transceivers?", "ans_a": "A. All transceivers use the same microphone connector type", "ans_d": "D. Un-keyed connectors allow any microphone to be connected", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. All transceivers using the same connector type are wired identically", "ans_b": "B. Some connectors include push-to-talk and voltages for powering the microphone"}, "T3A05": {"question": "When using a directional antenna, how might your station be able to access a distant repeater if buildings or obstructions are blocking the direct line of sight path?", "ans_a": "A. Change from vertical to horizontal polarization", "ans_d": "D. Increase the antenna SWR", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Try the long path", "ans_b": "B. Try to find a path that reflects signals to the repeater"}, "T3B02": {"question": "What property of a radio wave is used to describe its polarization?", "ans_a": "A. The orientation of the electric field", "ans_d": "D. The ratio of the velocity to the wavelength", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The ratio of the energy in the magnetic field to the energy in the electric field", "ans_b": "B. The orientation of the magnetic field"}, "T2A12": {"question": "Which of the following is a guideline to use when choosing an operating frequency for calling CQ?", "ans_a": "A. Listen first to be sure that no one else is using the frequency", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Make sure you are in your assigned band", "ans_b": "B. Ask if the frequency is in use"}, "T3B10": {"question": "What frequency range is referred to as HF?", "ans_a": "A. 300 to 3000 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 300 to 3000 kHz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 3 to 30 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 30 to 300 MHz"}, "T0C05": {"question": "Why do exposure limits vary with frequency?", "ans_a": "A. Lower frequency RF fields have more energy than higher frequency fields", "ans_d": "D. The human body absorbs more RF energy at some frequencies than at others", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Higher frequency RF fields are transient in nature", "ans_b": "B. Lower frequency RF fields do not penetrate the human body"}, "T9B01": {"question": "Why is it important to have a low SWR in an antenna system that uses coaxial cable feed line?", "ans_a": "A. To reduce television interference ", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. To prolong antenna life", "ans_b": "B. To allow the efficient transfer of power and reduce losses"}, "T6C07": {"question": "What is component 8 in figure T2?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Light emitting diode", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Regulator IC", "ans_b": "B. Inductor"}, "T0A06": {"question": "What is a good way to guard against electrical shock at your station?", "ans_a": "A. Use three-wire cords and plugs for all AC powered equipment", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Use a circuit protected by a ground-fault interrupter", "ans_b": "B. Connect all AC powered station equipment to a common safety ground"}, "T3C07": {"question": "What band is best suited for communicating via meteor scatter?", "ans_a": "A. 10 meters", "ans_d": "D. 70 cm", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 2 meters", "ans_b": "B. 6 meters"}, "T8C02": {"question": "Which of these items would be useful for a hidden transmitter hunt?", "ans_a": "A. Calibrated SWR meter", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A calibrated noise bridge", "ans_b": "B. A directional antenna"}, "T2B07": {"question": "What could cause your FM signal to interfere with stations on nearby frequencies?", "ans_a": "A. Microphone gain too high, causing over-deviation ", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Incorrect CTCSS Tone", "ans_b": "B. SWR too high"}, "T0A01": {"question": "Which of the following is a safety hazard of a 12-volt storage battery?", "ans_a": "A. Touching both terminals with the hands can cause electrical shock", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. RF emissions from the battery", "ans_b": "B. Shorting the terminals can cause burns, fire, or an explosion"}, "T0A05": {"question": "Why is it unwise to install a 20-ampere fuse in the place of a 5-ampere fuse?", "ans_a": "A. The larger fuse would be likely to blow because it is rated for higher current", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Excessive current could cause a fire", "ans_b": "B. The power supply ripple would greatly increase"}, "T5A09": {"question": "What is the name for a current that reverses direction on a regular basis?", "ans_a": "A. Alternating current", "ans_d": "D. Vertical current", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Circular current", "ans_b": "B. Direct current"}, "T8C03": {"question": "What popular operating activity involves contacting as many stations as possible during a specified period of time?", "ans_a": "A. Contesting", "ans_d": "D. Simulated emergency exercises", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Public service events", "ans_b": "B. Net operations"}, "T1F13": {"question": "When must the station licensee make the station and its records available for FCC inspection?", "ans_a": "A. At any time ten days after notification by the FCC of such an inspection", "ans_d": "D. Only when presented with a valid warrant by an FCC official or government agent", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Only after failing to comply with an FCC notice of violation", "ans_b": "B. At any time upon request by an FCC representative"}, "T5A12": {"question": "What term describes the number of times per second that an alternating current reverses direction?", "ans_a": "A. Pulse rate", "ans_d": "D. Frequency", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Wavelength", "ans_b": "B. Speed"}, "T0B04": {"question": "Which of the following is an important safety precaution to observe when putting up an antenna tower?", "ans_a": "A. Wear a ground strap connected to your wrist at all times", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Look for and stay clear of any overhead electrical wires", "ans_b": "B. Insulate the base of the tower to avoid lightning strikes"}, "T8C01": {"question": "Which of the following methods is used to locate sources of noise interference or jamming?", "ans_a": "A. Echolocation", "ans_d": "D. Phase locking", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Radio direction finding", "ans_b": "B. Doppler radar "}, "T7C13": {"question": "What does a dummy load consist of?", "ans_a": "A. A high-gain amplifier and a TR switch", "ans_d": "D. A 50 ohm reactance used to terminate a transmission line ", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A low voltage power supply and a DC relay", "ans_b": "B. A non-inductive resistor and a heat sink"}, "T3B11": {"question": "What is the approximate velocity of a radio wave as it travels through free space?", "ans_a": "A. 3000 kilometers per second", "ans_d": "D. 186,000 miles per hour", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 300,000 miles per hour", "ans_b": "B. 300,000,000 meters per second"}, "T6D10": {"question": "What is the function of component 2 in Figure T1?", "ans_a": "A. Give off light when current flows through it", "ans_d": "D. Convert electrical energy into radio waves", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Control the flow of current", "ans_b": "B. Supply electrical energy"}, "T7B09": {"question": "What is a Part 15 device?", "ans_a": "A. An unlicensed device that may emit low powered radio signals on frequencies used by a licensed service", "ans_d": "D. A type of test set used to determine whether a transmitter is in compliance with FCC regulation 91.15", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A device for long distance communications using special codes sanctioned by the International Amateur Radio Union", "ans_b": "B. A type of amateur radio that can legally be used in the citizen\u2019s band"}, "T5C04": {"question": "What is the basic unit of inductance?", "ans_a": "A. The coulomb", "ans_d": "D. The ohm", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The henry", "ans_b": "B. The farad"}, "T7C10": {"question": "Why should the outer jacket of coaxial cable be resistant to ultraviolet light?", "ans_a": "A. Ultraviolet resistant jackets prevent harmonic radiation", "ans_d": "D. Ultraviolet light can damage the jacket and allow water to enter the cable", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Ultraviolet and RF signals can mix together, causing interference", "ans_b": "B. Ultraviolet light can increase losses in the cable\u2019s jacket"}, "T0B06": {"question": "What is the minimum safe distance from a power line to allow when installing an antenna?", "ans_a": "A. Half the width of your property", "ans_d": "D. So that if the antenna falls unexpectedly, no part of it can come closer than 10 feet to the power wires", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 1/2 wavelength at the operating frequency", "ans_b": "B. The height of the power line above ground"}, "T1D04": {"question": "What is the only time an amateur station is authorized to transmit music?", "ans_a": "A. When incidental to an authorized retransmission of manned spacecraft communications", "ans_d": "D. When the music is transmitted above 1280 MHz", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. When the purpose is to interfere with an illegal transmission", "ans_b": "B. When the music produces no spurious emissions"}, "T9A09": {"question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a 6 meter 1/2-wavelength wire dipole antenna?", "ans_a": "A. 6", "ans_d": "D. 236", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 112", "ans_b": "B. 50"}, "T3C11": {"question": "Why do VHF and UHF radio signals usually travel somewhat farther than the visual line of sight distance between two stations?", "ans_a": "A. Radio signals move somewhat faster than the speed of light", "ans_d": "D. Radio waves are blocked by dust particles", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The Earth seems less curved to radio waves than to light", "ans_b": "B. Radio waves are not blocked by dust particles"}, "T2C05": {"question": "Which of the following describes the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service (RACES)? ", "ans_a": "A. A radio service using amateur frequencies for emergency management or civil defense communications", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. An emergency service using amateur operators certified by a civil defense organization as being enrolled in that organization", "ans_b": "B. A radio service using amateur stations for emergency management or civil defense communications"}, "T1A04": {"question": "Which of the following meets the FCC definition of harmful interference?", "ans_a": "A. Radio transmissions that annoy users of a repeater", "ans_d": "D. Static from lightning storms", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. That which seriously degrades, obstructs, or repeatedly interrupts a radio communication service operating in accordance with the Radio Regulations", "ans_b": "B. Unwanted radio transmissions that cause costly harm to radio station apparatus"}, "T7D01": {"question": "Which instrument would you use to measure electric potential or electromotive force?", "ans_a": "A. An ammeter", "ans_d": "D. An ohmmeter", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A wavemeter", "ans_b": "B. A voltmeter"}, "T1D10": {"question": "What is the meaning of the term \u201cbroadcasting\u201d in the FCC rules for the amateur services?", "ans_a": "A. Two-way transmissions by amateur stations", "ans_d": "D. Transmissions intended for reception by the general public ", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Transmission of messages directed only to amateur operators ", "ans_b": "B. Transmission of music"}, "T5B09": {"question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 5 watts to 10 watts?", "ans_a": "A. 2 dB", "ans_d": "D. 10 dB", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 5 dB", "ans_b": "B. 3 dB"}, "T5A01": {"question": "Electrical current is measured in which of the following units?", "ans_a": "A. Volts", "ans_d": "D. Amperes", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Ohms", "ans_b": "B. Watts"}, "T0C02": {"question": "Which of the following frequencies has the lowest value for Maximum Permissible Exposure limit?", "ans_a": "A. 3.5 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 1296 MHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 440 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 50 MHz"}, "T7D02": {"question": "What is the correct way to connect a voltmeter to a circuit?", "ans_a": "A. In series with the circuit", "ans_d": "D. In phase with the circuit", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. In quadrature with the circuit", "ans_b": "B. In parallel with the circuit"}, "T0C10": {"question": "Why is duty cycle one of the factors used to determine safe RF radiation exposure levels?", "ans_a": "A. It affects the average exposure of people to radiation", "ans_d": "D. It takes into account the thermal effects of the final amplifier", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. It takes into account the antenna feed line loss", "ans_b": "B. It affects the peak exposure of people to radiation"}, "T8B06": {"question": "Which of the following are inputs to a satellite tracking program?", "ans_a": "A. The weight of the satellite", "ans_d": "D. All of these answers are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The last observed time of zero Doppler shift", "ans_b": "B. The Keplerian elements"}, "T7D05": {"question": "What instrument is used to measure resistance?", "ans_a": "A. An oscilloscope", "ans_d": "D. An ohmmeter", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A noise bridge", "ans_b": "B. A spectrum analyzer"}, "T0C09": {"question": "How can you make sure your station stays in compliance with RF safety regulations?", "ans_a": "A. By informing the FCC of any changes made in your station", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. By making sure your antennas have low SWR", "ans_b": "B. By re-evaluating the station whenever an item of equipment is changed"}, "T8D08": {"question": "Which of the following may be included in packet transmissions?", "ans_a": "A. A check sum which permits error detection", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct ", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Automatic repeat request in case of error", "ans_b": "B. A header which contains the call sign of the station to which the information is being sent"}, "T6B08": {"question": "What does the abbreviation FET stand for?", "ans_a": "A. Field Effect Transistor", "ans_d": "D. Field Emission Thickness", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Free Electron Transition", "ans_b": "B. Fast Electron Transistor"}, "T0B01": {"question": "When should members of a tower work team wear a hard hat and safety glasses?", "ans_a": "A. At all times except when climbing the tower", "ans_d": "D. Only when the tower exceeds 30 feet in height", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. At all times when any work is being done on the tower", "ans_b": "B. At all times except when belted firmly to the tower"}, "T1C05": {"question": "Which of the following is a vanity call sign which a technician class amateur operator might select if available?", "ans_a": "A. K1XXX", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. W1XX", "ans_b": "B. KA1X"}, "T1B04": {"question": "Which amateur band are you using when your station is transmitting on 146.52 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. 2 meter band", "ans_d": "D. 6 meter band", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 14 meter band", "ans_b": "B. 20 meter band"}, "T6A01": {"question": "What electrical component is used to oppose the flow of current in a DC circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Inductor", "ans_d": "D. Transformer", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Voltmeter", "ans_b": "B. Resistor"}, "T9B10": {"question": "What electrical difference exists between the smaller RG-58 and larger RG-8 coaxial cables?", "ans_a": "A. There is no significant difference between the two types", "ans_d": "D. RG-58 cable can handle higher power levels", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. RG-8 cable has less loss at a given frequency", "ans_b": "B. RG-58 cable has less loss at a given frequency"}, "T5C03": {"question": "What is the ability to store energy in a magnetic field called?", "ans_a": "A. Admittance", "ans_d": "D. Inductance", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Resistance", "ans_b": "B. Capacitance"}, "T0C08": {"question": "Which of the following actions might amateur operators take to prevent exposure to RF radiation in excess of FCC-supplied limits?", "ans_a": "A. Relocate antennas", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Increase the duty cycle", "ans_b": "B. Relocate the transmitter"}, "T1D08": {"question": "In which of the following circumstances may the control operator of an amateur station receive compensation for operating the station? ", "ans_a": "A. When engaging in communications on behalf of their employer", "ans_d": "D. When notifying other amateur operators of the availability for sale or trade of apparatus", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. When re-broadcasting weather alerts during a RACES net", "ans_b": "B. When the communication is incidental to classroom instruction at an educational institution"}, "T7D03": {"question": "How is an ammeter usually connected to a circuit?", "ans_a": "A. In series with the circuit", "ans_d": "D. In phase with the circuit", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. In quadrature with the circuit", "ans_b": "B. In parallel with the circuit"}, "T1B13": {"question": "Which emission may be used between 219 and 220 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. Spread spectrum", "ans_d": "D. Fast-scan television", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. SSB voice", "ans_b": "B. Data"}, "T6A03": {"question": "What electrical parameter is controlled by a potentiometer?", "ans_a": "A. Inductance", "ans_d": "D. Field strength", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Capacitance", "ans_b": "B. Resistance"}, "T4B01": {"question": "What may happen if a transmitter is operated with the microphone gain set too high?", "ans_a": "A. The output power might be too high", "ans_d": "D. The SWR might increase", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The frequency might vary", "ans_b": "B. The output signal might become distorted"}, "T3B05": {"question": "How does the wavelength of a radio wave relate to its frequency?", "ans_a": "A. The wavelength gets longer as the frequency increases", "ans_d": "D. The wavelength depends on the bandwidth of the signal", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. There is no relationship between wavelength and frequency", "ans_b": "B. The wavelength gets shorter as the frequency increases"}, "T5C13": {"question": "What are the units of impedance? ", "ans_a": "A. Volts", "ans_d": "D. Ohms", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Coulombs", "ans_b": "B. Amperes"}, "T1A01": {"question": "Which of the following is a purpose of the Amateur Radio Service as stated in the FCC rules and regulations?", "ans_a": "A. Providing personal radio communications for as many citizens as possible", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct ", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Advancing skills in the technical and communication phases of the radio art", "ans_b": "B. Providing communications for international non-profit organizations"}, "T8A01": {"question": "Which of the following is a form of amplitude modulation?", "ans_a": "A. Spread-spectrum", "ans_d": "D. Phase shift keying", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Single sideband", "ans_b": "B. Packet radio"}, "T2B01": {"question": "What is the term used to describe an amateur station that is transmitting and receiving on the same frequency?", "ans_a": "A. Full duplex communication", "ans_d": "D. Multiplex communication", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Simplex communication", "ans_b": "B. Diplex communication"}, "T6C01": {"question": "What is the name for standardized representations of components in an electrical wiring diagram?", "ans_a": "A. Electrical depictions", "ans_d": "D. Component callouts", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Schematic symbols", "ans_b": "B. Grey sketch"}, "T0A09": {"question": "What kind of hazard is presented by a conventional 12-volt storage battery?", "ans_a": "A. It emits ozone which can be harmful to the atmosphere", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Explosive gas can collect if not properly vented", "ans_b": "B. Shock hazard due to high voltage"}, "T3B03": {"question": "What are the two components of a radio wave?", "ans_a": "A. AC and DC", "ans_d": "D. Ionizing and non-ionizing radiation", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Electric and magnetic fields", "ans_b": "B. Voltage and current"}, "T0B10": {"question": "Which of the following is true concerning grounding conductors used for lightning protection?", "ans_a": "A. Only non-insulated wire must be used", "ans_d": "D. Common grounds must be avoided", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Sharp bends must be avoided", "ans_b": "B. Wires must be carefully routed with precise right-angle bends"}, "T6A07": {"question": "What electrical component is usually composed of a coil of wire?", "ans_a": "A. Switch", "ans_d": "D. Inductor", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Diode", "ans_b": "B. Capacitor"}, "T5D12": {"question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 2 amperes flows through it?", "ans_a": "A. 8 volts", "ans_d": "D. 20 volts", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 12 volts", "ans_b": "B. 0.2 volts"}, "T0C04": {"question": "What factors affect the RF exposure of people near an amateur station antenna?", "ans_a": "A. Frequency and power level of the RF field", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Radiation pattern of the antenna", "ans_b": "B. Distance from the antenna to a person"}, "T5C12": {"question": "What is meant by the term impedance? ", "ans_a": "A. It is a measure of the opposition to AC current flow in a circuit", "ans_d": "D. It is a measure of the power handling capability of a component", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. It is a measure of the Q or Quality Factor of a component", "ans_b": "B. It is the inverse of resistance"}, "T1A06": {"question": "Which of the following services are protected from interference by amateur signals under all circumstances?", "ans_a": "A. Citizens Radio Service", "ans_d": "D.\u00a0Radionavigation Service", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Land Mobile Radio Service", "ans_b": "B.\u00a0Broadcast Service"}, "T8B11": {"question": "What is a commonly used method of sending signals to and from a digital satellite?", "ans_a": "A. USB AFSK", "ans_d": "D. WSJT", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. FM Packet", "ans_b": "B. PSK31"}, "T9A05": {"question": "How would you change a dipole antenna to make it resonant on a higher frequency?", "ans_a": "A. Lengthen it", "ans_d": "D. Add capacitive loading to the ends of the radiating wires", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Shorten it", "ans_b": "B. Insert coils in series with radiating wires"}, "T5A07": {"question": "Which of the following is a good electrical conductor?", "ans_a": "A. Glass", "ans_d": "D. Rubber", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Copper", "ans_b": "B. Wood"}, "T1C07": {"question": "What may result when correspondence from the FCC is returned as undeliverable because the grantee failed to provide the correct mailing address?", "ans_a": "A. Fine or imprisonment", "ans_d": "D. A reduction of one rank in operator class", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Require the licensee to be re-examined", "ans_b": "B. Revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license"}, "T8A07": {"question": "What is the primary advantage of single sideband over FM for voice transmissions?", "ans_a": "A. SSB signals are easier to tune", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. SSB signals have narrower bandwidth", "ans_b": "B. SSB signals are less susceptible to interference"}, "T9B02": {"question": "What is the impedance of the most commonly used coaxial cable in typical amateur radio installations?", "ans_a": "A. 8 ohms", "ans_d": "D. 12 ohms", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 600 ohms", "ans_b": "B. 50 ohms"}, "T1A10": {"question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of an amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. A station in the Amateur Radio Service consisting of the apparatus necessary for carrying on radio communications", "ans_d": "D. Any radio station for hobby use", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Any radio station operated by a non-professional", "ans_b": "B. A building where Amateur Radio receivers, transmitters, and RF power amplifiers are installed"}, "T7A08": {"question": "Which of the following describes combining speech with an RF carrier signal?-", "ans_a": "A. Impedance matching", "ans_d": "D. Low-pass filtering", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Modulation", "ans_b": "B. Oscillation"}, "T2A08": {"question": "What is the meaning of the procedural signal \u201cCQ\u201d?", "ans_a": "A. Call on the quarter hour", "ans_d": "D. Calling any station", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Only the called station should transmit", "ans_b": "B. A new antenna is being tested (no station should answer)"}, "T4A05": {"question": "Where should an in-line SWR meter be connected to monitor the standing wave ratio of the station antenna system?", "ans_a": "A. In series with the feed line, between the transmitter and antenna", "ans_d": "D. In series with the power supply cable, as close as possible to the radio", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. In parallel with the push-to-talk line and the antenna", "ans_b": "B. In series with the station's ground"}, "T1E01": {"question": "When is an amateur station permitted to transmit without a control operator?", "ans_a": "A. When using automatic control, such as in the case of a repeater", "ans_d": "D. Never", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. When the transmitting station is an auxiliary station", "ans_b": "B. When the station licensee is away and another licensed amateur is using the station"}, "T1C02": {"question": "Which of the following is a valid US amateur radio station call sign?", "ans_a": "A. KMA3505", "ans_d": "D. 11Q1176", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. KDKA", "ans_b": "B. W3ABC"}, "T8C08": {"question": "What is required in place of on-air station identification when sending signals to a radio control model using amateur frequencies?", "ans_a": "A. Voice identification must be transmitted every 10 minutes", "ans_d": "D. A flag must be affixed to the transmitter antenna with the station call sign in 1 inch high letters or larger", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A label indicating the licensee\u2019s name, call sign and address must be affixed to the transmitter", "ans_b": "B. Morse code ID must be sent once per hour"}, "T3A07": {"question": "What type of wave carries radio signals between transmitting and receiving stations?", "ans_a": "A. Electromagnetic", "ans_d": "D. Magnetostrictive", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Surface acoustic", "ans_b": "B. Electrostatic"}, "T6B06": {"question": "How is the cathode lead of a semiconductor diode usually identified?", "ans_a": "A. With the word cathode", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. With the letter C", "ans_b": "B. With a stripe"}, "T1B09": {"question": "Why should you not set your transmit frequency to be exactly at the edge of an amateur band or sub-band?", "ans_a": "A. To allow for calibration error in the transmitter frequency display", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. To allow for transmitter frequency drift", "ans_b": "B. So that modulation sidebands do not extend beyond the band edge"}, "T9B04": {"question": "What does an antenna tuner do?", "ans_a": "A. It matches the antenna system impedance to the transceiver's output impedance", "ans_d": "D. It automatically selects the proper antenna for the frequency band being used", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. It allows an antenna to be used on both transmit and receive", "ans_b": "B. It helps a receiver automatically tune in weak stations"}, "T2B10": {"question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are receiving interference from other stations?", "ans_a": "A. QRM", "ans_d": "D. QSB", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. QTH", "ans_b": "B. QRN"}, "T1D12": {"question": "Under which of the following circumstances may an amateur radio station engage in broadcasting?", "ans_a": "A. Under no circumstances", "ans_d": "D. At any time as long as the material being transmitted did not originate from a commercial broadcast station", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. At any time as long as no music is transmitted", "ans_b": "B. When transmitting code practice, information bulletins, or transmissions necessary to provide emergency communications"}, "T3B09": {"question": "What are the frequency limits of the UHF spectrum?", "ans_a": "A. 30 to 300 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 300 to 3000 MHz", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 300 to 3000 kHz", "ans_b": "B. 30 to 300 MHz"}, "T1F07": {"question": "Which of the following restrictions apply when a non-licensed person is allowed to speak to a foreign station using a station under the control of a Technician Class control operator?", "ans_a": "A. The person must be a U.S. citizen", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The licensed control operator must do the station identification", "ans_b": "B. The foreign station must be one with which the U.S. has a third party agreement"}, "T9A14": {"question": "Which of the following terms describes a type of loading when referring to an antenna?", "ans_a": "A. Inserting an inductor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it electrically longer", "ans_d": "D. Making the antenna heavier so it will resist wind effects when in motion", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Installing a spring at the base of the antenna to absorb the effects of collisions with other objects", "ans_b": "B. Inserting a resistor in the radiating portion of the antenna to make it resonant"}, "T0A07": {"question": "Which of these precautions should be taken when installing devices for lightning protection in a coaxial cable feed line?", "ans_a": "A. Include a parallel bypass switch for each protector so that it can be switched out of the circuit when running high power", "ans_d": "D. Ground all of the protectors to a common plate which is in turn connected to an external ground", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Keep the ground wires from each protector separate and connected to station ground", "ans_b": "B. Include a series switch in the ground line of each protector to prevent RF overload from inadvertently damaging the protector"}, "T4B04": {"question": "What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency on your transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. Enable the CTCSS tones", "ans_d": "D. Use the scan mode to select the desired frequency", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Disable the CTCSS tones", "ans_b": "B. Store the frequency in a memory channel"}, "T8A03": {"question": "Which type of voice mode is most often used for long-distance (weak signal) contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?", "ans_a": "A. FM", "ans_d": "D. PM", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. SSB", "ans_b": "B. DRM"}, "T7D06": {"question": "Which of the following might damage a multimeter?", "ans_a": "A. Measuring a voltage too small for the chosen scale", "ans_d": "D. Not allowing it to warm up properly", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Attempting to measure voltage when using the resistance setting", "ans_b": "B. Leaving the meter in the milliamps position overnight"}, "T9B06": {"question": "Which of the following connectors is most suitable for frequencies above 400 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. A UHF (PL-259/SO-239) connector", "ans_d": "D. A DB-25 connector", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. An RS-213 connector", "ans_b": "B. A Type N connector"}, "T3C04": {"question": "Which of the following propagation types is most commonly associated with occasional strong over-the-horizon signals on the 10, 6, and 2 meter bands?", "ans_a": "A. Backscatter", "ans_d": "D. Gray-line propagation", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. D layer absorption", "ans_b": "B. Sporadic E"}, "T5C08": {"question": "What is the formula used to calculate electrical power in a DC circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Power (P) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)", "ans_d": "D. Power (P) equals voltage (E) plus current (I)", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Power (P) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)", "ans_b": "B. Power (P) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)"}, "T2C08": {"question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of good emergency traffic handling? ", "ans_a": "A. Passing messages exactly as received", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Communicating messages to the news media for broadcast outside the disaster area", "ans_b": "B. Making decisions as to whether or not messages should be relayed or delivered "}, "T4A10": {"question": "What is the source of a high-pitched whine that varies with engine speed in a mobile transceiver\u2019s receive audio?", "ans_a": "A. The ignition system", "ans_d": "D. Anti-lock braking system controllers", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The electric fuel pump", "ans_b": "B. The alternator"}, "T7B05": {"question": "How can overload of a non-amateur radio or TV receiver by an amateur signal be reduced or eliminated?", "ans_a": "A. Block the amateur signal with a filter at the antenna input of the affected receiver", "ans_d": "D. Switch the transmitter to a narrow-band mode", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Switch the transmitter from FM to SSB", "ans_b": "B. Block the interfering signal with a filter on the amateur transmitter"}, "T3C08": {"question": "What causes tropospheric ducting?", "ans_a": "A. Discharges of lightning during electrical storms", "ans_d": "D. Temperature inversions in the atmosphere", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Updrafts from hurricanes and tornadoes", "ans_b": "B. Sunspots and solar flares"}, "T0A04": {"question": "What is the purpose of a fuse in an electrical circuit?", "ans_a": "A. To prevent power supply ripple from damaging a circuit", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. To limit current to prevent shocks", "ans_b": "B. To interrupt power in case of overload"}, "T5D09": {"question": "What is the current flowing through a 24-ohm resistor connected across 240 volts?", "ans_a": "A. 24,000 amperes", "ans_d": "D. 216 amperes", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 10 amperes", "ans_b": "B. 0.1 amperes"}, "T7D04": {"question": "Which instrument is used to measure electric current?", "ans_a": "A. An ohmmeter", "ans_d": "D. An ammeter", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A voltmeter", "ans_b": "B. A wavemeter"}, "T3C09": {"question": "What is generally the best time for long-distance 10 meter band propagation via the F layer?", "ans_a": "A. From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of high sunspot activity", "ans_d": "D. From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of low sunspot activity", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. From dawn to shortly after sunset during periods of low sunspot activity", "ans_b": "B. From shortly after sunset to dawn during periods of high sunspot activity"}, "T7C07": {"question": "What happens to power lost in a feed line?", "ans_a": "A. It increases the SWR", "ans_d": "D. It can cause distortion of your signal", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. It is converted into heat", "ans_b": "B. It comes back into your transmitter and could cause damage"}, "T5B03": {"question": "How many volts are equal to one kilovolt?", "ans_a": "A. One one-thousandth of a volt", "ans_d": "D. One million volts", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. One thousand volts", "ans_b": "B. One hundred volts"}, "T5D11": {"question": "What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 1 ampere flows through it?", "ans_a": "A. 1 volt", "ans_d": "D. 9 volts", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 11 volts", "ans_b": "B. 10 volts"}, "T1A02": {"question": "Which agency regulates and enforces the rules for the Amateur Radio Service in the United States?", "ans_a": "A. FEMA", "ans_d": "D. Homeland Security", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The FCC", "ans_b": "B. The ITU"}, "T3C12": {"question": "Which of the following bands may provide long distance communications during the peak of the sunspot cycle?", "ans_a": "A. Six or ten meters", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 70 centimeters or 1.25 meters", "ans_b": "B. 23 centimeters"}, "T5D06": {"question": "What is the resistance of a circuit that draws 4 amperes from a 12-volt source?", "ans_a": "A. 3 ohms", "ans_d": "D. 8 Ohms", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 48 ohms", "ans_b": "B. 16 ohms"}, "T7C09": {"question": "Which of the following is the most common cause for failure of coaxial cables?", "ans_a": "A. Moisture contamination", "ans_d": "D. Overloading", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The velocity factor exceeds 1.0", "ans_b": "B. Gamma rays"}, "T5C06": {"question": "What does the abbreviation \u201cRF\u201d refer to? ", "ans_a": "A. Radio frequency signals of all types", "ans_d": "D. Reflective force in antenna transmission lines ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The real frequency transmitted as opposed to the apparent frequency", "ans_b": "B. The resonant frequency of a tuned circuit"}, "T6B02": {"question": "What electronic component allows current to flow in only one direction?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Driven Element", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Diode", "ans_b": "B. Fuse"}, "T7B01": {"question": "What can you do if you are told your FM handheld or mobile transceiver is over-deviating?", "ans_a": "A. Talk louder into the microphone", "ans_d": "D. Talk farther away from the microphone", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Change to a higher power level", "ans_b": "B. Let the transceiver cool off"}, "T8C06": {"question": "How is access to an IRLP node accomplished?", "ans_a": "A. By obtaining a password which is sent via voice to the node", "ans_d": "D. By using CTCSS tone codes", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. By entering the proper Internet password", "ans_b": "B. By using DTMF signals"}, "T8B04": {"question": "Which amateur stations may make contact with an amateur station on the International Space Station using 2 meter and 70 cm band amateur radio frequencies?", "ans_a": "A. Only members of amateur radio clubs at NASA facilities", "ans_d": "D. You cannot talk to the ISS on amateur radio frequencies", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Only the astronaut's family members who are hams", "ans_b": "B. Any amateur holding a Technician or higher class license"}, "T2B13": {"question": "Which of the following is true of the use of SSB phone in amateur bands above 50 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. It is permitted only by holders of a General Class or higher license", "ans_d": "D. It is permitted only on when power is limited to no more than 100 watts", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. It is permitted in at least some portion of all the amateur bands above 50 MHz", "ans_b": "B. It is permitted only on repeaters"}, "T7B07": {"question": "Which of the following may be useful in correcting a radio frequency interference problem?", "ans_a": "A. Snap-on ferrite chokes", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Band-reject and band-pass filters", "ans_b": "B. Low-pass and high-pass filters"}, "T3A04": {"question": "What can happen if the antennas at opposite ends of a VHF or UHF line of sight radio link are not using the same polarization?", "ans_a": "A. The modulation sidebands might become inverted", "ans_d": "D. Nothing significant will happen", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Signals have an echo effect on voices", "ans_b": "B. Signals could be significantly weaker"}, "T2B05": {"question": "What determines the amount of deviation of an FM (as opposed to PM) signal?", "ans_a": "A. Both the frequency and amplitude of the modulating signal", "ans_d": "D. The relative phase of the modulating signal and the carrier", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The amplitude of the modulating signal", "ans_b": "B. The frequency of the modulating signal"}, "T4A06": {"question": "Which of the following would be connected between a transceiver and computer in a packet radio station?", "ans_a": "A. Transmatch", "ans_d": "D. Antenna", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Terminal node controller", "ans_b": "B. Mixer"}, "T2B12": {"question": "Under what circumstances should you consider communicating via simplex rather than a repeater?", "ans_a": "A. When the stations can communicate directly without using a repeater", "ans_d": "D. Only if you have simplex modulation capability", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Only when third party traffic is not being passed", "ans_b": "B. Only when you have an endorsement for simplex operation on your license"}, "T1F08": {"question": "Which indicator is required by the FCC to be transmitted after a station call sign?", "ans_a": "A. /M when operating mobile", "ans_d": "D. /KT, /AE or /AG when using new license privileges earned by CSCE while waiting for an upgrade to a previously issued license to appear in the FCC license database", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. / followed the FCC Region number when operating out of the region in which the license was issued", "ans_b": "B. /R when operating a repeater"}, "T8A02": {"question": "What type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF packet radio transmissions?", "ans_a": "A. FM", "ans_d": "D. Spread Spectrum", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. AM", "ans_b": "B. SSB"}, "T9B11": {"question": "Which of the following types of feed line has the lowest loss at VHF and UHF?", "ans_a": "A. 50-ohm flexible coax", "ans_d": "D. 75-ohm flexible coax", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Air-insulated hard line", "ans_b": "B. Multi-conductor unbalanced cable"}, "T9A03": {"question": "Which of the following describes a simple dipole mounted so the conductor is parallel to the Earth's surface?", "ans_a": "A. A ground wave antenna", "ans_d": "D. A vertically polarized antenna ", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A rhombic antenna", "ans_b": "B. A horizontally polarized antenna"}, "T1F11": {"question": "To which foreign stations do the FCC rules authorize the transmission of non-emergency third party communications?", "ans_a": "A. Any station whose government permits such communications", "ans_d": "D. Those in ITU Region 3 only", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Those in ITU Regions 2 and 3 only", "ans_b": "B. Those in ITU Region 2 only"}, "T8B01": {"question": "Who may be the control operator of a station communicating through an amateur satellite or space station?", "ans_a": "A. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator", "ans_d": "D. Any amateur whose license privileges allow them to transmit on the satellite uplink frequency", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator who is also an AMSAT member", "ans_b": "B. A General Class licensee or higher licensee who has a satellite operator certification"}, "T1C06": {"question": "From which of the following locations may an FCC-licensed amateur station transmit, in addition to places where the FCC regulates communications?", "ans_a": "A. From within any country that belongs to the International Telecommunications Union", "ans_d": "D. From any vessel or craft located in international waters and documented or registered in the United States", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. From anywhere within in ITU Regions 2 and 3", "ans_b": "B. From within any country that is a member of the United Nations "}, "T5D03": {"question": "What formula is used to calculate resistance in a circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)", "ans_d": "D. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) added to current (I)", "ans_b": "B. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)"}, "T7C11": {"question": "What is a disadvantage of air core coaxial cable when compared to foam or solid dielectric types?", "ans_a": "A. It has more loss per foot", "ans_d": "D. It cannot be used at below freezing temperatures", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. It requires special techniques to prevent water absorption", "ans_b": "B. It cannot be used for VHF or UHF antennas"}, "T5B01": {"question": "How many milliamperes is 1.5 amperes?", "ans_a": "A. 15 milliamperes", "ans_d": "D. 15,000 milliamperes", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 1,500 milliamperes", "ans_b": "B. 150 milliamperes"}, "T1A09": {"question": "Who selects a Frequency Coordinator?", "ans_a": "A. The FCC Office of Spectrum Management and Coordination Policy ", "ans_d": "D. FCC Regional Field Office", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Amateur operators in a local or regional area whose stations are eligible to be auxiliary or repeater stations", "ans_b": "B. The local chapter of the Office of National Council of Independent Frequency Coordinators"}, "T6A06": {"question": "What type of electrical component stores energy in a magnetic field?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Diode", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Inductor", "ans_b": "B. Capacitor"}, "T1A13": {"question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telecommand?", "ans_a": "A. An instruction bulletin issued by the FCC", "ans_d": "D. An instruction from a VEC", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance", "ans_b": "B. A one-way radio transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument"}, "T2C10": {"question": "What is the preamble in a formal traffic message?", "ans_a": "A. The first paragraph of the message text", "ans_d": "D. The information needed to track the message as it passes through the amateur radio traffic handling system", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The priority handling indicator for the message", "ans_b": "B. The message number"}, "T5B11": {"question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 20 watts to 200 watts?", "ans_a": "A. 10 dB", "ans_d": "D. 28 dB", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 18 dB", "ans_b": "B. 12 dB"}, "T3A09": {"question": "Which of the following results from the fact that skip signals refracted from the ionosphere are elliptically polarized?", "ans_a": "A. Digital modes are unusable", "ans_d": "D. Both the transmitting and receiving antennas must be of the same polarization", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. FM voice is unusable", "ans_b": "B. Either vertically or horizontally polarized antennas may be used for transmission or reception"}, "T4A04": {"question": "Where must a filter be installed to reduce harmonic emissions from your station?", "ans_a": "A. Between the transmitter and the antenna", "ans_d": "D. At the microphone", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. At the station power supply", "ans_b": "B. Between the receiver and the transmitter"}, "T2A01": {"question": "What is the most common repeater frequency offset in the 2 meter band?", "ans_a": "A. Plus 500 kHz", "ans_d": "D. Only plus 600 kHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Minus 500 kHz", "ans_b": "B. Plus or minus 600 kHz"}, "T7C03": {"question": "What, in general terms, is standing wave ratio (SWR)?", "ans_a": "A. A measure of how well a load is matched to a transmission line", "ans_d": "D. An indication of the quality of your station\u2019s ground connection", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The transmitter efficiency ratio", "ans_b": "B. The ratio of high to low impedance in a feed line"}, "T8A05": {"question": "Which of the following types of emission has the narrowest bandwidth?", "ans_a": "A. FM voice", "ans_d": "D. Slow-scan TV", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. CW", "ans_b": "B. SSB voice"}, "T9A10": {"question": "In which direction is the radiation strongest from a half-wave dipole antenna in free space?", "ans_a": "A. Equally in all directions", "ans_d": "D. In the direction of the feed line", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Broadside to the antenna", "ans_b": "B. Off the ends of the antenna"}, "T5B10": {"question": "What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power decrease from 12 watts to 3 watts?", "ans_a": "A. -1 dB", "ans_d": "D. -9 dB", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. -6 dB", "ans_b": "B. -3 dB"}, "T1E11": {"question": "Who does the FCC presume to be the control operator of an amateur station, unless documentation to the contrary is in the station records?", "ans_a": "A. The station custodian", "ans_d": "D. The station licensee", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The person operating the station equipment", "ans_b": "B. The third party participant"}, "T2A03": {"question": "What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 70 cm band?", "ans_a": "A. Plus or minus 5 MHz", "ans_d": "D. Plus 600 kHz", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Minus 600 kHz", "ans_b": "B. Plus or minus 600 kHz"}, "T6D01": {"question": "Which of the following devices or circuits changes an alternating current into a varying direct current signal?", "ans_a": "A. Transformer", "ans_d": "D. Reflector", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Amplifier", "ans_b": "B. Rectifier"}, "T2C02": {"question": "What is one way to recharge a 12-volt lead-acid station battery if the commercial power is out?", "ans_a": "A. Cool the battery in ice for several hours", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Connect the battery in parallel with a vehicle\u2019s battery and run the engine", "ans_b": "B. Add acid to the battery"}, "T8D06": {"question": "What does the abbreviation PSK mean?", "ans_a": "A. Pulse Shift Keying", "ans_d": "D. Phased Slide Keying", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Packet Short Keying", "ans_b": "B. Phase Shift Keying"}, "T0B08": {"question": "What is considered to be a proper grounding method for a tower?", "ans_a": "A. A single four-foot ground rod, driven into the ground no more than 12 inches from the base", "ans_d": "D. A connection between the tower base and a cold water pipe", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Separate eight-foot long ground rods for each tower leg, bonded to the tower and each other", "ans_b": "B. A ferrite-core RF choke connected between the tower and ground"}, "T9A04": {"question": "What is a disadvantage of the \u201crubber duck\u201d antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers?", "ans_a": "A. It does not transmit or receive as effectively as a full-sized antenna", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. If the rubber end cap is lost it will unravel very quickly", "ans_b": "B. It transmits a circularly polarized signal"}, "T5D01": {"question": "What formula is used to calculate current in a circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Current (I) equals voltage (E) multiplied by resistance (R)", "ans_d": "D. Current (I) equals voltage (E) minus resistance (R)", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Current (I) equals voltage (E) added to resistance (R)", "ans_b": "B. Current (I) equals voltage (E) divided by resistance (R)"}, "T8D03": {"question": "Which of the following devices provides data to the transmitter when sending automatic position reports from a mobile amateur radio station?", "ans_a": "A. The vehicle speedometer", "ans_d": "D. A Global Positioning System receiver", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A connection to a broadcast FM sub-carrier receiver", "ans_b": "B. A WWV receiver"}, "T7D08": {"question": "Which of the following types of solder is best for radio and electronic use?", "ans_a": "A. Acid-core solder", "ans_d": "D. Aluminum solder", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Rosin-core solder", "ans_b": "B. Silver solder"}, "T8D05": {"question": "Which of the following is an application of APRS (Automatic Packet Reporting System)?", "ans_a": "A. Providing real time tactical digital communications in conjunction with a map showing the locations of stations", "ans_d": "D. Providing information on the number of stations signed into a repeater", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Providing voice over Internet connection between repeaters", "ans_b": "B. Showing automatically the number of packets transmitted via PACTOR during a specific time interval"}, "T7B08": {"question": "What should you do if something in a neighbor\u2019s home is causing harmful interference to your amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. Work with your neighbor to identify the offending device", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Check your station and make sure it meets the standards of good amateur practice", "ans_b": "B. Politely inform your neighbor about the rules that prohibit the use of devices which cause interference"}, "T7D07": {"question": "Which of the following measurements are commonly made using a multimeter?", "ans_a": "A. SWR and RF power", "ans_d": "D. Voltage and resistance", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Impedance and reactance", "ans_b": "B. Signal strength and noise"}, "T4B05": {"question": "Which of the following would reduce ignition interference to a receiver?", "ans_a": "A. Change frequency slightly", "ans_d": "D. Use the RIT control", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Turn on the noise blanker", "ans_b": "B. Decrease the squelch setting"}, "T7A02": {"question": "What is a transceiver?", "ans_a": "A.\u00a0A type of antenna switch", "ans_d": "D. A type of antenna matching network", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A component in a repeater which filters out unwanted interference", "ans_b": "B. A unit combining the functions of a transmitter and a receiver"}, "T7A10": {"question": "What device increases the low-power output from a handheld transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. A voltage divider", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. An impedance network", "ans_b": "B. An RF power amplifier"}, "T6C11": {"question": "What is component 4 in figure T3?", "ans_a": "A. Antenna", "ans_d": "D. Ground", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Dummy load", "ans_b": "B. Transmitter"}, "T1F09": {"question": "What type of amateur station simultaneously retransmits the signal of another amateur station on a different channel or channels?", "ans_a": "A. Beacon station", "ans_d": "D. Message forwarding station", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Repeater station", "ans_b": "B. Earth station"}, "T3C05": {"question": "Which of the following effects might cause radio signals to be heard despite obstructions between the transmitting and receiving stations?", "ans_a": "A. Knife-edge diffraction", "ans_d": "D. Doppler shift", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Quantum tunneling ", "ans_b": "B. Faraday rotation"}, "T4B07": {"question": "What does the term \u201cRIT\u201d mean?", "ans_a": "A. Receiver Input Tone", "ans_d": "D. Remote Input Transmitter", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Rectifier Inverter Test", "ans_b": "B. Receiver Incremental Tuning"}, "T4B08": {"question": "What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. Permits monitoring several modes at once", "ans_d": "D. Increases the amount of offset between receive and transmit frequencies", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Increases the number of frequencies that can be stored in memory", "ans_b": "B. Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode"}, "T2B04": {"question": "Which of the following common problems might cause you to be able to hear but not access a repeater even when transmitting with the proper offset?", "ans_a": "A. The repeater receiver may require an audio tone burst for access", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The repeater receiver may require a DCS tone sequence for access", "ans_b": "B. The repeater receiver may require a CTCSS tone for access"}, "T1F12": {"question": "How many persons are required to be members of a club for a club station license to be issued by the FCC?", "ans_a": "A. At least 5", "ans_d": "D. At least 2", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A trustee and 2 officers", "ans_b": "B. At least 4"}, "T6D11": {"question": "What is a simple resonant or tuned circuit?", "ans_a": "A. An inductor and a capacitor connected in series or parallel to form a filter", "ans_d": "D. A circuit designed to provide high fidelity audio", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A resistor circuit used for reducing standing wave ratio", "ans_b": "B. A type of voltage regulator"}, "T9A06": {"question": "What type of antennas are the quad, Yagi, and dish?", "ans_a": "A. Non-resonant antennas", "ans_d": "D. Isotropic antennas", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Directional antennas", "ans_b": "B. Loop antennas"}, "T5D05": {"question": "What is the resistance in a circuit for which the applied voltage is 12 volts and the current flow is 1.5 amperes?", "ans_a": "A. 18 ohms", "ans_d": "D. 13.5 ohms", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 8 ohms", "ans_b": "B. 0.125 ohms"}, "T1D07": {"question": "What types of amateur stations can automatically retransmit the signals of other amateur stations?", "ans_a": "A. Auxiliary, beacon, or Earth stations", "ans_d": "D. Earth, repeater, or space stations", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Beacon, repeater, or space stations", "ans_b": "B. Auxiliary, repeater, or space stations"}, "T4A03": {"question": "Which is a good reason to use a regulated power supply for communications equipment?", "ans_a": "A. It prevents voltage fluctuations from reaching sensitive circuits", "ans_d": "D. Power consumption is independent of load", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A fuse or circuit breaker regulates the power", "ans_b": "B. A regulated power supply has FCC approval"}, "T5C09": {"question": "How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 13.8 volts DC and the current is 10 amperes?", "ans_a": "A. 138 watts", "ans_d": "D. 3.8 watts", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 23.8 watts", "ans_b": "B. 0.7 watts"}, "T2A07": {"question": "Which of the following is true when making a test transmission?", "ans_a": "A. Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 15 seconds", "ans_d": "D. Station identification is required at least every ten minutes during the test and at the end of the test", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Station identification is only required once an hour when the transmissions are for test purposes only", "ans_b": "B. Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 1 watt"}, "T1C10": {"question": "How soon after passing the examination for your first amateur radio license may you operate a transmitter on an amateur service frequency? ", "ans_a": "A. Immediately", "ans_d": "D. You must wait until you receive your license in the mail from the FCC", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. As soon as your operator/station license grant appears in the FCC\u2019s license database", "ans_b": "B. 30 days after the test date"}, "T5B04": {"question": "How many volts are equal to one microvolt?", "ans_a": "A. One one-millionth of a volt", "ans_d": "D. One one-thousandth of a volt", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. One thousand kilovolts", "ans_b": "B. One million volts"}, "T8C11": {"question": "What name is given to an amateur radio station that is used to connect other amateur stations to the Internet?", "ans_a": "A. A gateway", "ans_d": "D. A beacon", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A digipeater", "ans_b": "B. A repeater"}, "T1B02": {"question": "Why are the frequency assignments for some U.S. Territories different from those in the 50 U.S. States?", "ans_a": "A. Some U. S. Territories are located in ITU regions other than region 2", "ans_d": "D. Any territory that was in existence before the ratification of the Communications Act of 1934 is exempt from FCC frequency regulations", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Territorial frequency allocations must also include those of adjacent countries", "ans_b": "B. Territorial governments are allowed to select their own frequency allocations"}, "T0A10": {"question": "What can happen if a lead-acid storage battery is charged or discharged too quickly?", "ans_a": "A. The battery could overheat and give off flammable gas or explode", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The memory effect will reduce the capacity of the battery", "ans_b": "B. The voltage can become reversed"}, "T8D11": {"question": "What is an ARQ transmission system?", "ans_a": "A. A special transmission format limited to video signals", "ans_d": "D. A method of compressing the data in a message so more information can be sent in a shorter time ", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A digital scheme whereby the receiving station detects errors and sends a request to the sending station to retransmit the information ", "ans_b": "B. A system used to encrypt command signals to an amateur radio satellite"}, "T2A05": {"question": "How should you respond to a station calling CQ?", "ans_a": "A. Transmit CQ followed by the other station\u2019s call sign", "ans_d": "D. Transmit a signal report followed by your call sign", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Transmit the other station\u2019s call sign followed by your call sign", "ans_b": "B. Transmit your call sign followed by the other station\u2019s call sign"}, "T9A12": {"question": "What is a reason to use a properly mounted 5/8 wavelength antenna for VHF or UHF mobile service?", "ans_a": "A. It offers a lower angle of radiation and more gain than a 1/4 wavelength antenna and usually provides improved coverage", "ans_d": "D. The 5/8 wavelength antenna offers a 10-times power gain over a 1/4 wavelength design ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The 5/8 wavelength antenna completely eliminates distortion caused by reflected signals", "ans_b": "B. It features a very high angle of radiation and is better for communicating via a repeater"}, "T0A03": {"question": "What is connected to the green wire in a three-wire electrical AC plug?", "ans_a": "A. Neutral", "ans_d": "D. The white wire", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Safety ground", "ans_b": "B. Hot"}, "T8D01": {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a digital communications method?", "ans_a": "A. Packet", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. MFSK", "ans_b": "B. PSK31"}, "T1F01": {"question": "What type of identification is being used when identifying a station on the air as Race Headquarters?", "ans_a": "A. Tactical call sign", "ans_d": "D. Broadcast station", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. SSID", "ans_b": "B. An official call sign reserved for RACES drills"}, "T6D08": {"question": "Which of the following is used together with an inductor to make a tuned circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Capacitor", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Potentiometer", "ans_b": "B. Zener diode"}, "T7C08": {"question": "What instrument other than an SWR meter could you use to determine if a feed line and antenna are properly matched?", "ans_a": "A. Voltmeter", "ans_d": "D. Directional wattmeter", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Iambic pentameter", "ans_b": "B. Ohmmeter"}, "T0B03": {"question": "Under what circumstances is it safe to climb a tower without a helper or observer?", "ans_a": "A. When no electrical work is being performed", "ans_d": "D. Never", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. When the work being done is not more than 20 feet above the ground", "ans_b": "B. When no mechanical work is being performed"}, "T2A09": {"question": "What brief statement is often transmitted in place of \u201cCQ\u201d to indicate that you are listening on a repeater?", "ans_a": "A. The words \u201cHello test\u201d followed by your call sign", "ans_d": "D. The letters \u201cQSY\u201d followed by your call sign", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The repeater call sign followed by your call sign", "ans_b": "B. Your call sign "}, "T0A11": {"question": "What kind of hazard might exist in a power supply when it is turned off and disconnected?", "ans_a": "A. Static electricity could damage the grounding system", "ans_d": "D. You might receive an electric shock from the charged stored in large capacitors", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The fuse might blow if you remove the cover", "ans_b": "B. Circulating currents inside the transformer might cause damage"}, "T1C08": {"question": "What is the normal term for an FCC-issued primary station/operator amateur radio license grant?", "ans_a": "A. Five years", "ans_d": "D. Twenty years", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Ten years", "ans_b": "B. Life"}, "T6B12": {"question": "What is the term that describes a transistor's ability to amplify a signal?", "ans_a": "A. Gain", "ans_d": "D. On resistance", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Forward voltage drop", "ans_b": "B. Forward resistance"}, "T0C11": {"question": "What is the definition of duty cycle during the averaging time for RF exposure? ", "ans_a": "A. The difference between the lowest power output and the highest power output of a transmitter", "ans_d": "D. The percentage of time that a transmitter is not transmitting", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The percentage of time that a transmitter is transmitting", "ans_b": "B. The difference between the PEP and average power output of a transmitter"}, "T2A06": {"question": "What must an amateur operator do when making on-air transmissions to test equipment or antennas?", "ans_a": "A. Properly identify the transmitting station", "ans_d": "D. State the purpose of the test during the test procedure", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Notify the FCC of the test transmission", "ans_b": "B. Make test transmissions only after 10:00 p.m. local time"}, "T0C12": {"question": "How does RF radiation differ from ionizing radiation (radioactivity)?", "ans_a": "A. RF radiation does not have sufficient energy to cause genetic damage", "ans_d": "D. RF radiation is perfectly safe", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. RF radiation is limited in range to a few feet", "ans_b": "B. RF radiation can only be detected with an RF dosimeter"}, "T1F10": {"question": "Who is accountable should a repeater inadvertently retransmit communications that violate the FCC rules?", "ans_a": "A. The control operator of the originating station", "ans_d": "D. Both the originating station and the repeater owner", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The owner of the repeater", "ans_b": "B. The control operator of the repeater"}, "T6C06": {"question": "What is component 6 in figure T2?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Transistor", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Regulator IC", "ans_b": "B. Capacitor"}, "T1A03": {"question": "Which part of the FCC regulations contains the rules governing the Amateur Radio Service?", "ans_a": "A. Part 73", "ans_d": "D. Part 97", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Part 90", "ans_b": "B. Part 95"}, "T4A07": {"question": "How is a computer\u2019s sound card used when conducting digital communications using a computer?", "ans_a": "A. The sound card communicates between the computer CPU and the video display", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The sound card provides audio to the microphone input and converts received audio to digital form", "ans_b": "B. The sound card records the audio frequency for video display"}, "T3B06": {"question": "What is the formula for converting frequency to approximate wavelength in meters?", "ans_a": "A. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz multiplied by 300", "ans_d": "D. Wavelength in meters equals 300 divided by frequency in megahertz", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in megahertz divided by 300", "ans_b": "B. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz divided by 300"}, "T0A08": {"question": "What safety equipment should always be included in home-built equipment that is powered from 120V AC power circuits?", "ans_a": "A. A fuse or circuit breaker in series with the AC hot conductor", "ans_d": "D. A capacitor across the AC power source", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. An inductor in series with the AC power source", "ans_b": "B. An AC voltmeter across the incoming power source"}, "T8A10": {"question": "What is the typical bandwidth of analog fast-scan TV transmissions on the 70 cm band?", "ans_a": "A. More than 10 MHz", "ans_d": "D. About 1 MHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. About 3 MHz", "ans_b": "B. About 6 MHz"}, "T0B11": {"question": "Which of the following establishes grounding requirements for an amateur radio tower or antenna?", "ans_a": "A. FCC Part 97 Rules", "ans_d": "D. Underwriters Laboratories' recommended practices", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. FAA tower lighting regulations", "ans_b": "B. Local electrical codes"}, "T7C01": {"question": "What is the primary purpose of a dummy load?", "ans_a": "A. To prevent the radiation of signals when making tests", "ans_d": "D. To improve the signal to noise ratio of your receiver", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. To improve the radiation from your antenna", "ans_b": "B. To prevent over-modulation of your transmitter"}, "T6A05": {"question": "What type of electrical component consists of two or more conductive surfaces separated by an insulator?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Capacitor", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Oscillator", "ans_b": "B. Potentiometer"}, "T4B06": {"question": "Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal seems too high or low?", "ans_a": "A. The AGC or limiter", "ans_d": "D. The receiver RIT or clarifier", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The tone squelch", "ans_b": "B. The bandwidth selection"}, "T3A02": {"question": "Why are UHF signals often more effective from inside buildings than VHF signals?", "ans_a": "A. VHF signals lose power faster over distance", "ans_d": "D. UHF antennas are more efficient than VHF antennas", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. This is incorrect; VHF works better than UHF inside buildings", "ans_b": "B. The shorter wavelength allows them to more easily penetrate the structure of buildings"}, "T1A05": {"question": "Which of the following is a purpose of the Amateur Radio Service rules and regulations as defined by the FCC?", "ans_a": "A. Enhancing international goodwill", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Training of operators in military radio operating procedures", "ans_b": "B. Providing inexpensive communication for local emergency organizations"}, "T6D09": {"question": "What is the name of a device that combines several semiconductors and other components into one package?", "ans_a": "A. Transducer", "ans_d": "D. Transformer", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Integrated circuit", "ans_b": "B. Multi-pole relay"}, "T6C08": {"question": "What is component 9 in figure T2?", "ans_a": "A. Variable capacitor", "ans_d": "D. Variable transformer", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Variable resistor", "ans_b": "B. Variable inductor"}, "T7C04": {"question": "What reading on an SWR meter indicates a perfect impedance match between the antenna and the feed line?", "ans_a": "A. 2 to 1", "ans_d": "D. 10 to 1", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 1 to 1", "ans_b": "B. 1 to 3"}, "T7D09": {"question": "What is the characteristic appearance of a cold solder joint?", "ans_a": "A. Dark black spots", "ans_d": "D. A greenish tint", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A grainy or dull surface", "ans_b": "B. A bright or shiny surface"}, "T3A01": {"question": "What should you do if another operator reports that your station\u2019s 2 meter signals were strong just a moment ago, but now they are weak or distorted?", "ans_a": "A. Change the batteries in your radio to a different type", "ans_d": "D. Try moving a few feet or changing the direction of your antenna if possible, as reflections may be causing multi-path distortion", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Ask the other operator to adjust his squelch control", "ans_b": "B. Turn on the CTCSS tone"}, "T4B02": {"question": "Which of the following can be used to enter the operating frequency on a modern transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. The keypad or VFO knob", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The Automatic Frequency Control", "ans_b": "B. The CTCSS or DTMF encoder"}, "T2B02": {"question": "What is the term used to describe the use of a sub-audible tone transmitted with normal voice audio to open the squelch of a receiver?", "ans_a": "A. Carrier squelch", "ans_d": "D. CTCSS", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. DTMF", "ans_b": "B. Tone burst"}, "T1E03": {"question": "Who must designate the station control operator?", "ans_a": "A. The station licensee", "ans_d": "D. The ITU", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The frequency coordinator", "ans_b": "B. The FCC"}, "T8B09": {"question": "What causes spin fading when referring to satellite signals?", "ans_a": "A. Circular polarized noise interference radiated from the sun ", "ans_d": "D. Interfering signals within the satellite uplink band ", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Doppler shift of the received signal", "ans_b": "B. Rotation of the satellite and its antennas"}, "T5A11": {"question": "What is the basic unit of electromotive force?", "ans_a": "A. The volt", "ans_d": "D. The ohm", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The ampere", "ans_b": "B. The watt"}, "T1D09": {"question": "Under which of the following circumstances are amateur stations authorized to transmit signals related to broadcasting, program production, or news gathering, assuming no other means is available?", "ans_a": "A. Only where such communications directly relate to the immediate safety of human life or protection of property", "ans_d": "D. Only when using amateur repeaters linked to the Internet", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Only where noncommercial programming is gathered and supplied exclusively to the National Public Radio network ", "ans_b": "B. Only when broadcasting communications to or from the space shuttle"}, "T6C05": {"question": "What is component 4 in figure T1?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Ground symbol", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Battery", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T9A02": {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding vertical antennas?", "ans_a": "A. The magnetic field is perpendicular to the Earth", "ans_d": "D. The phase is reversed", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The phase is inverted", "ans_b": "B. The electric field is perpendicular to the Earth"}, "T7B12": {"question": "What might be the first step to resolve cable TV interference from your ham radio transmission?", "ans_a": "A. Add a low pass filter to the TV antenna input", "ans_d": "D. Be sure all TV coaxial connectors are installed properly", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Add a preamplifier to the TV antenna input", "ans_b": "B. Add a high pass filter to the TV antenna input"}, "T2B08": {"question": "Which of the following applies when two stations transmitting on the same frequency interfere with each other?", "ans_a": "A. Common courtesy should prevail, but no one has absolute right to an amateur frequency", "ans_d": "D. The station which has the weakest signal has priority on the frequency", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Whoever has been on the frequency the longest has priority on the frequency", "ans_b": "B. Whoever has the strongest signal has priority on the frequency"}, "T1C03": {"question": "What types of international communications are permitted by an FCC-licensed amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. Communications incidental to the purposes of the amateur service and remarks of a personal character", "ans_d": "D. Any communications that would be permitted by an international broadcast station", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Only communications incidental to contest exchanges, all other communications are prohibited", "ans_b": "B. Communications incidental to conducting business or remarks of a personal nature"}, "T4A08": {"question": "Which type of conductor is best to use for RF grounding?", "ans_a": "A. Round stranded wire ", "ans_d": "D. Flat strap", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Twisted-pair cable", "ans_b": "B. Round copper-clad steel wire"}, "T6A11": {"question": "Which of the following battery types is not rechargeable?", "ans_a": "A. Nickel-cadmium", "ans_d": "D. Lithium-ion", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Lead-acid ", "ans_b": "B. Carbon-zinc"}, "T8B05": {"question": "What is a satellite beacon?", "ans_a": "A. The primary transmit antenna on the satellite", "ans_d": "D. A transmission from a space station that contains information about a satellite", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A reflective surface on the satellite", "ans_b": "B. An indicator light that that shows where to point your antenna"}, "T7D10": {"question": "What is probably happening when an ohmmeter, connected across an unpowered circuit, initially indicates a low resistance and then shows increasing resistance with time?", "ans_a": "A. The ohmmeter is defective", "ans_d": "D. The circuit is a relaxation oscillator", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The circuit contains a large inductor", "ans_b": "B. The circuit contains a large capacitor"}, "T7C05": {"question": "What is the approximate SWR value above which the protection circuits in most solid-state transmitters begin to reduce transmitter power?", "ans_a": "A. 2 to 1", "ans_d": "D. 10 to 1 ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 6 to 1", "ans_b": "B. 1 to 2"}, "T5C02": {"question": "What is the basic unit of capacitance?", "ans_a": "A. The farad", "ans_d": "D. The henry", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The volt", "ans_b": "B. The ohm"}, "T9B03": {"question": "Why is coaxial cable used more often than any other feed line for amateur radio antenna systems?", "ans_a": "A. It is easy to use and requires few special installation considerations", "ans_d": "D. It is less expensive than any other types of feed line", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. It can handle more power than any other type of feed line", "ans_b": "B. It has less loss than any other type of feed line"}, "T3A03": {"question": "What antenna polarization is normally used for long-distance weak-signal CW and SSB contacts using the VHF and UHF bands?", "ans_a": "A. Right-hand circular", "ans_d": "D. Vertical", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Horizontal", "ans_b": "B. Left-hand circular"}, "T5B08": {"question": "How many microfarads are 1,000,000 picofarads?", "ans_a": "A. 0.001 microfarads", "ans_d": "D. 1,000,000,000 microfarads", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 1000 microfarads", "ans_b": "B. 1 microfarad"}, "T2A02": {"question": "What is the national calling frequency for FM simplex operations in the 70 cm band?", "ans_a": "A. 146.520 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 446.000 MHz", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 432.100 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 145.000 MHz"}, "T6A04": {"question": "What electrical component stores energy in an electric field?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Diode", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Inductor", "ans_b": "B. Capacitor"}, "T3C03": {"question": "What is a characteristic of VHF signals received via auroral reflection?", "ans_a": "A. Signals from distances of 10,000 or more miles are common", "ans_d": "D. These types of signals are generally strongest when your antenna is aimed west", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. These types of signals occur only during winter nighttime hours", "ans_b": "B. The signals exhibit rapid fluctuations of strength and often sound distorted"}, "T7C02": {"question": "Which of the following instruments can be used to determine if an antenna is resonant at the desired operating frequency?", "ans_a": "A. A VTVM", "ans_d": "D. A frequency counter", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. A Q meter", "ans_b": "B. An antenna analyzer"}, "T6B01": {"question": "What class of electronic components is capable of using a voltage or current signal to control current flow?", "ans_a": "A. Capacitors", "ans_d": "D. Transistors", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Resistors", "ans_b": "B. Inductors"}, "T7A11": {"question": "Where is an RF preamplifier installed?", "ans_a": "A. Between the antenna and receiver", "ans_d": "D. At the receiver's audio output", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Between a transmitter and antenna tuner", "ans_b": "B. At the output of the transmitter's power amplifier"}, "T5A05": {"question": "What is the electrical term for the electromotive force (EMF) that causes electron flow?", "ans_a": "A. Voltage", "ans_d": "D. Inductance", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Capacitance", "ans_b": "B. Ampere-hours"}, "T1C12": {"question": "Who may select a desired call sign under the vanity call sign rules?", "ans_a": "A. Only licensed amateurs with general or extra class licenses", "ans_d": "D. Any licensed amateur", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Only an amateur licensee who has been licensed continuously for more than 10 years", "ans_b": "B. Only licensed amateurs with an extra class license"}, "T5D08": {"question": "What is the current flowing through a 100-ohm resistor connected across 200 volts?", "ans_a": "A. 20,000 amperes", "ans_d": "D. 100 amperes", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 2 amperes", "ans_b": "B. 0.5 amperes"}, "T5A02": {"question": "Electrical power is measured in which of the following units?", "ans_a": "A. Volts", "ans_d": "D. Amperes", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Ohms", "ans_b": "B. Watts"}, "T0C01": {"question": "What type of radiation are VHF and UHF radio signals?", "ans_a": "A. Gamma radiation", "ans_d": "D. Non-ionizing radiation", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Alpha radiation", "ans_b": "B. Ionizing radiation"}, "T7B03": {"question": "Which of the following may be a cause of radio frequency interference?", "ans_a": "A. Fundamental overload", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Spurious emissions", "ans_b": "B. Harmonics"}, "T6D06": {"question": "What component is commonly used to change 120V AC house current to a lower AC voltage for other uses?", "ans_a": "A. Variable capacitor", "ans_d": "D. Diode", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Transistor", "ans_b": "B. Transformer"}, "T3A08": {"question": "Which of the following is a likely cause of irregular fading of signals received by ionospheric reflection?", "ans_a": "A. Frequency shift due to Faraday rotation", "ans_d": "D. Intermodulation distortion ", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Random combining of signals arriving via different paths ", "ans_b": "B. Interference from thunderstorms"}, "T3A10": {"question": "What may occur if data signals propagate over multiple paths?", "ans_a": "A. Transmission rates can be increased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed", "ans_d": "D. Error rates are likely to increase", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. No significant changes will occur if the signals are transmitting using FM", "ans_b": "B. Transmission rates must be decreased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed"}, "T9A01": {"question": "What is a beam antenna?", "ans_a": "A. An antenna built from aluminum I-beams", "ans_d": "D. An antenna that reverses the phase of received signals", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction", "ans_b": "B. An omnidirectional antenna invented by Clarence Beam"}, "T1D03": {"question": "When is the transmission of codes or ciphers that hide the meaning of a message allowed by an amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. Only during contests", "ans_d": "D. Only when frequencies above 1280 MHz are used", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Only when transmitting control commands to space stations or radio control craft", "ans_b": "B. Only when operating mobile"}, "T1E10": {"question": "Which of the following is an example of remote control as defined in Part 97?", "ans_a": "A. Repeater operation", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Controlling a model aircraft, boat or car by amateur radio", "ans_b": "B. Operating the station over the Internet"}, "T3B04": {"question": "How fast does a radio wave travel through free space?", "ans_a": "A. At the speed of light", "ans_d": "D. Its speed increases as the frequency increases", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Its speed is inversely proportional to its wavelength", "ans_b": "B. At the speed of sound"}, "T6C13": {"question": "Which of the following is accurately represented in electrical circuit schematic diagrams?", "ans_a": "A. Wire lengths", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The way components are interconnected", "ans_b": "B. Physical appearance of components"}, "T5C01": {"question": "What is the ability to store energy in an electric field called?", "ans_a": "A. Inductance", "ans_d": "D. Capacitance", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Tolerance ", "ans_b": "B. Resistance"}, "T7A05": {"question": "What is the name of a circuit that generates a signal of a desired frequency?", "ans_a": "A. Reactance modulator", "ans_d": "D. Oscillator", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Low-pass filter", "ans_b": "B. Product detector"}, "T2B06": {"question": "What happens when the deviation of an FM transmitter is increased?", "ans_a": "A. Its signal occupies more bandwidth", "ans_d": "D. Asymmetric modulation occurs", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Its output power and bandwidth increases", "ans_b": "B. Its output power increases"}, "T7C06": {"question": "What does an SWR reading of 4:1 indicate?", "ans_a": "A. Loss of -4dB", "ans_d": "D. Impedance mismatch", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Gain of +4dB", "ans_b": "B. Good impedance match"}, "T6D12": {"question": "Which of the following is a common reason to use shielded wire?", "ans_a": "A. To decrease the resistance of DC power connections", "ans_d": "D. To couple the wire to other signals", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. To prevent coupling of unwanted signals to or from the wire", "ans_b": "B. To increase the current carrying capability of the wire"}, "T6B10": {"question": "What are the three electrodes of a PNP or NPN transistor?", "ans_a": "A. Emitter, base, and collector", "ans_d": "D. Cathode, drift cavity, and collector", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Cathode, grid, and plate", "ans_b": "B. Source, gate, and drain"}, "T0C13": {"question": "If the averaging time for exposure is 6 minutes, how much power density is permitted if the signal is present for 3 minutes and absent for 3 minutes rather than being present for the entire 6 minutes? ", "ans_a": "A. 3 times as much", "ans_d": "D. There is no adjustment allowed for shorter exposure times", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 2 times as much", "ans_b": "B. 1/2 as much"}, "T6B07": {"question": "What does the abbreviation LED stand for?", "ans_a": "A. Low Emission Diode", "ans_d": "D. Long Echo Delay", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Liquid Emission Detector", "ans_b": "B. Light Emitting Diode"}, "T5B13": {"question": "If a frequency readout shows a reading of 2425 MHz, what frequency is that in GHz?", "ans_a": "A. 0.002425 GHZ", "ans_d": "D. 2425 GHz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 2.425 GHz", "ans_b": "B. 24.25 GHz"}, "T1B10": {"question": "Which of the bands above 30 MHz that are available to Technician Class operators have mode-restricted sub-bands?", "ans_a": "A. The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 70 cm bands", "ans_d": "D. The 2 meter and 70 cm bands", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 1.25 meter bands", "ans_b": "B. The 2 meter and 13 cm bands"}, "T1E05": {"question": "What is an amateur station control point?", "ans_a": "A. The location of the station\u2019s transmitting antenna", "ans_d": "D. The mailing address of the station licensee", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The location at which the control operator function is performed", "ans_b": "B. The location of the station transmitting apparatus "}, "T1E12": {"question": "When, under normal circumstances, may a Technician Class licensee be the control operator of a station operating in an exclusive Extra Class operator segment of the amateur bands?", "ans_a": "A. At no time", "ans_d": "D. When using a club station whose trustee is an Extra Class operator licensee", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. As part of a multi-operator contest team", "ans_b": "B. When operating a special event station"}, "T0C07": {"question": "What could happen if a person accidentally touched your antenna while you were transmitting?", "ans_a": "A. Touching the antenna could cause television interference", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. They might develop radiation poisoning", "ans_b": "B. They might receive a painful RF burn"}, "T1D06": {"question": "What, if any, are the restrictions concerning transmission of language that may be considered indecent or obscene?", "ans_a": "A. The FCC maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies", "ans_d": "D. There is no such prohibition ", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The ITU maintains a list of words that are not permitted to be used on amateur frequencies", "ans_b": "B. Any such language is prohibited"}, "T1C11": {"question": "If your license has expired and is still within the allowable grace period, may you continue to operate a transmitter on amateur service frequencies?", "ans_a": "A. No, transmitting is not allowed until the FCC license database shows that the license has been renewed", "ans_d": "D. Yes, for up to two years", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Yes, but only during authorized nets", "ans_b": "B. Yes, but only if you identify using the suffix GP"}, "T6C09": {"question": "What is component 4 in figure T2?", "ans_a": "A. Variable inductor", "ans_d": "D. Transformer", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Potentiometer", "ans_b": "B. Double-pole switch"}, "T3B07": {"question": "What property of radio waves is often used to identify the different frequency bands?", "ans_a": "A. The approximate wavelength", "ans_d": "D. The voltage standing wave ratio of waves", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The time it takes for waves to travel one mile", "ans_b": "B. The magnetic intensity of waves"}, "T8D07": {"question": "What is PSK31?", "ans_a": "A. A high-rate data transmission mode", "ans_d": "D. A low-rate data transmission mode ", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A method of compressing digital television signals", "ans_b": "B. A method of reducing noise interference to FM signals"}, "T8C04": {"question": "Which of the following is good procedure when contacting another station in a radio contest?", "ans_a": "A. Be sure to sign only the last two letters of your call if there is a pileup calling the station", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Send only the minimum information needed for proper identification and the contest exchange", "ans_b": "B. Work the station twice to be sure that you are in his log"}, "T7B11": {"question": "What is a symptom of RF feedback in a transmitter or transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. Excessive SWR at the antenna connection", "ans_d": "D. Frequent blowing of power supply fuses", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Reports of garbled, distorted, or unintelligible transmissions", "ans_b": "B. The transmitter will not stay on the desired frequency"}, "T6B04": {"question": "Which of the following components can be made of three layers of semiconductor material?", "ans_a": "A. Alternator", "ans_d": "D. Pentagrid converter", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Triode", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T9B09": {"question": "What might cause erratic changes in SWR readings?", "ans_a": "A. The transmitter is being modulated", "ans_d": "D. Interference from other stations is distorting your signal", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The transmitter is being over-modulated", "ans_b": "B. A loose connection in an antenna or a feed line"}, "T1C09": {"question": "What is the grace period following the expiration of an amateur license within which the license may be renewed?", "ans_a": "A. Two years", "ans_d": "D. Ten years ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Five years", "ans_b": "B. Three years"}, "T3B01": {"question": "What is the name for the distance a radio wave travels during one complete cycle?", "ans_a": "A. Wave speed", "ans_d": "D. Wave spread", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Wavelength", "ans_b": "B. Waveform"}, "T6C10": {"question": "What is component 3 in figure T3?", "ans_a": "A. Connector", "ans_d": "D. Variable inductor", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Variable capacitor", "ans_b": "B. Meter"}, "T1A08": {"question": "Which of the following entities recommends transmit/receive channels and other parameters for auxiliary and repeater stations?", "ans_a": "A. Frequency Spectrum Manager", "ans_d": "D. International Telecommunications Union", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. FCC Regional Field Office ", "ans_b": "B. Frequency Coordinator"}, "T6A08": {"question": "What electrical component is used to connect or disconnect electrical circuits?", "ans_a": "A. Magnetron", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Thermistor", "ans_b": "B. Switch"}, "T1C13": {"question": "For which licenses classes are new licenses currently available from the FCC?", "ans_a": "A. Novice, Technician, General, Advanced", "ans_d": "D. Technician, General, Amateur Extra", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Novice, Technician Plus, General, Advanced", "ans_b": "B. Technician, Technician Plus, General, Advanced"}, "T4B09": {"question": "Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth to select in order to minimize noise and interference for SSB reception?", "ans_a": "A. 500 Hz", "ans_d": "D. 5000 Hz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 2400 Hz", "ans_b": "B. 1000 Hz"}, "T3A11": {"question": "Which part of the atmosphere enables the propagation of radio signals around the world?", "ans_a": "A. The stratosphere", "ans_d": "D. The magnetosphere", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The ionosphere", "ans_b": "B. The troposphere"}, "T4A11": {"question": "Where should the negative return connection of a mobile transceiver's power cable be connected?", "ans_a": "A. At the battery or engine block ground strap", "ans_d": "D. Through the transceiver\u2019s mounting bracket", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. To any metal part of the vehicle", "ans_b": "B. At the antenna mount"}, "T5D07": {"question": "What is the current flow in a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a resistance of 80 ohms?", "ans_a": "A. 9600 amperes", "ans_d": "D. 1.5 amperes", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. 0.667 amperes", "ans_b": "B. 200 amperes"}, "T2B11": {"question": "Which Q signal indicates that you are changing frequency?", "ans_a": "A. QRU", "ans_d": "D. QRZ", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. QSL", "ans_b": "B. QSY"}, "T8C13": {"question": "What is the Internet Radio Linking Project (IRLP)?", "ans_a": "A. A technique to connect amateur radio systems, such as repeaters, via the Internet using Voice Over Internet Protocol", "ans_d": "D. A technique for measuring signal strength of an amateur transmitter via the Internet", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A system for informing amateurs in real time of the frequency of active DX stations", "ans_b": "B. A system for providing access to websites via amateur radio"}, "T9A08": {"question": "What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?", "ans_a": "A. 112", "ans_d": "D. 12", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 19", "ans_b": "B. 50"}, "T2C11": {"question": "What is meant by the term \u201ccheck\u201d in reference to a formal traffic message?", "ans_a": "A. The check is a count of the number of words or word equivalents in the text portion of the message", "ans_d": "D. The check is a box on the message form that tells you the message was received", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The check is a list of stations that have relayed the message", "ans_b": "B. The check is the value of a money order attached to the message"}, "T1D02": {"question": "On which of the following occasions may an FCC-licensed amateur station exchange messages with a U.S. military station?", "ans_a": "A. During an Armed Forces Day Communications Test", "ans_d": "D. During a propagation test", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. During an Independence Day celebration", "ans_b": "B. During a Memorial Day Celebration"}, "T1B03": {"question": "Which frequency is within the 6 meter band?", "ans_a": "A. 49.00 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 222.15 MHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 28.50 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 52.525 MHz"}, "T1F06": {"question": "Which of the following formats of a self-assigned indicator is acceptable when identifying using a phone transmission?", "ans_a": "A. KL7CC stroke W3", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. KL7CC slash W3", "ans_b": "B. KL7CC slant W3"}, "T8A06": {"question": "Which sideband is normally used for 10 meter HF, VHF and UHF single-sideband communications?", "ans_a": "A. Upper sideband", "ans_d": "D. Inverted sideband", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Suppressed sideband", "ans_b": "B. Lower sideband"}, "T1F05": {"question": "What method of call sign identification is required for a station transmitting phone signals?", "ans_a": "A. Send the call sign followed by the indicator RPT", "ans_d": "D. Send the call sign using only phone emission", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Send the call sign followed by the indicator R", "ans_b": "B. Send the call sign using CW or phone emission"}, "T5C10": {"question": "How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the current is 2.5 amperes?", "ans_a": "A. 4.8 watts", "ans_d": "D. 0.208 watts", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 14.5 watts", "ans_b": "B. 30 watts"}, "T1D01": {"question": "With which countries are FCC-licensed amateur stations prohibited from exchanging communications?", "ans_a": "A. Any country whose administration has notified the ITU that it objects to such communications", "ans_d": "D. Any country in violation of the War Powers Act of 1934", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Any country engaged in hostilities with another country", "ans_b": "B. Any country whose administration has notified the ARRL that it objects to such communications"}, "T5A04": {"question": "What is the name for a current that flows only in one direction?", "ans_a": "A. Alternating current", "ans_d": "D. Smooth current", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Normal current", "ans_b": "B. Direct current"}, "T3C02": {"question": "Which of the following might be happening when VHF signals are being received from long distances?", "ans_a": "A. Signals are being reflected from outer space", "ans_d": "D. Signals are being refracted from a sporadic E layer", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Signals are being reflected by lightning storms in your area", "ans_b": "B. Signals are arriving by sub-surface ducting"}, "T1E08": {"question": "Which of the following is an example of automatic control?", "ans_a": "A. Repeater operation", "ans_d": "D. Using a computer or other device to automatically identify ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Using a computer or other device to automatically send CW", "ans_b": "B. Controlling the station over the Internet"}, "T0A02": {"question": "How does current flowing through the body cause a health hazard?", "ans_a": "A. By heating tissue", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. It causes involuntary muscle contractions", "ans_b": "B. It disrupts the electrical functions of cells"}, "T2B03": {"question": "Which of the following describes the muting of receiver audio controlled solely by the presence or absence of an RF signal?", "ans_a": "A. Tone squelch", "ans_d": "D. Modulated carrier", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. CTCSS", "ans_b": "B. Carrier squelch"}, "T8B02": {"question": "How much transmitter power should be used on the uplink frequency of an amateur satellite or space station?", "ans_a": "A. The maximum power of your transmitter", "ans_d": "D. Never more than 1 watt", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. No more than half the rating of your linear amplifier", "ans_b": "B. The minimum amount of power needed to complete the contact"}, "T6B09": {"question": "What are the names of the two electrodes of a diode?", "ans_a": "A. Plus and minus", "ans_d": "D. Gate and base", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Anode and cathode", "ans_b": "B. Source and drain"}, "T1D05": {"question": "When may amateur radio operators use their stations to notify other amateurs of the availability of equipment for sale or trade?", "ans_a": "A. When the equipment is normally used in an amateur station and such activity is not conducted on a regular basis", "ans_d": "D. When the equipment is not the personal property of either the station licensee or the control operator or their close relatives", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. When the asking price is less than its appraised value", "ans_b": "B. When the asking price is $100.00 or less"}, "T1B06": {"question": "Which 23 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class licensee?", "ans_a": "A. 2315 MHz", "ans_d": "D. 146.52 MHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 3390 MHz", "ans_b": "B. 1296 MHz"}, "T6D07": {"question": "Which of the following is commonly used as a visual indicator?", "ans_a": "A. LED", "ans_d": "D. Bipolar transistor", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Zener diode", "ans_b": "B. FET"}, "T1A12": {"question": "Which of the following is a permissible use of the Amateur Radio Service? ", "ans_a": "A. Broadcasting music and videos to friends", "ans_d": "D. Allowing a person to conduct radio experiments and to communicate with other licensed hams around the world", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Providing low-cost communications for start-up businesses", "ans_b": "B. Providing a way for amateur radio operators to earn additional income by using their stations to pass messages"}, "T1B01": {"question": "What is the ITU?", "ans_a": "A. An agency of the United States Department of Telecommunications Management", "ans_d": "D. A department of the FCC", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. An independent frequency coordination agency", "ans_b": "B. A United Nations agency for information and communication technology issues"}, "T5C07": {"question": "What is a usual name for electromagnetic waves that travel through space?", "ans_a": "A. Gravity waves", "ans_d": "D. Pressure waves", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Radio waves", "ans_b": "B. Sound waves"}, "T6A09": {"question": "What electrical component is used to protect other circuit components from current overloads?", "ans_a": "A. Fuse", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Inductor", "ans_b": "B. Capacitor"}, "T1C04": {"question": "When are you allowed to operate your amateur station in a foreign country?", "ans_a": "A. When the foreign country authorizes it", "ans_d": "D. When you are communicating with non-licensed individuals in another country", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. When authorization permits amateur communications in a foreign language", "ans_b": "B. When there is a mutual agreement allowing third party communications"}, "T5A06": {"question": "How much voltage does a mobile transceiver usually require?", "ans_a": "A. About 12 volts", "ans_d": "D. About 240 volts", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. About 120 volts", "ans_b": "B. About 30 volts"}, "T2A10": {"question": "What is a band plan, beyond the privileges established by the FCC?", "ans_a": "A. A voluntary guideline for using different modes or activities within an amateur band", "ans_d": "D. A plan devised by a club to indicate frequency band usage", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A list of scheduled net frequencies", "ans_b": "B. A mandated list of operating schedules"}, "T5B02": {"question": "What is another way to specify a radio signal frequency of 1,500,000 hertz?", "ans_a": "A. 1500 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 150 kHz", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 15 GHz", "ans_b": "B. 1500 MHz"}, "T6D03": {"question": "What type of switch is represented by component 3 in figure T2?", "ans_a": "A. Single-pole single-throw", "ans_d": "D. Double-pole double-throw", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Double-pole single-throw", "ans_b": "B. Single-pole double-throw"}, "T1B12": {"question": "Why are frequency assignments for U.S. stations operating maritime mobile not the same everywhere in the world?", "ans_a": "A.\u00a0Amateur maritime mobile stations in international waters must conform to the frequency assignments of the country nearest to their vessel", "ans_d": "D. Amateur frequency assignments are different in each of the 90 ITU zones", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Frequency assignments are determined by the captain of the vessel", "ans_b": "B. Amateur frequency assignments can vary among the three ITU regions"}, "T7A04": {"question": "Which term describes the ability of a receiver to discriminate between multiple signals?", "ans_a": "A. Discrimination ratio", "ans_d": "D. Harmonic Distortion", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Selectivity", "ans_b": "B. Sensitivity"}, "T2B09": {"question": "Which of the following methods is encouraged by the FCC when identifying your station when using phone?", "ans_a": "A. Use of a phonetic alphabet", "ans_d": "D. Increase your signal to full power when identifying", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Repeat your call sign three times", "ans_b": "B. Send your call sign in CW as well as voice"}, "T8C12": {"question": "What is meant by Voice Over Internet Protocol (VoIP) as used in amateur radio?", "ans_a": "A. A set of rules specifying how to identify your station when linked over the Internet to another station", "ans_d": "D. A method of delivering voice communications over the Internet using digital techniques ", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. A technique for measuring the modulation quality of a transmitter using remote sites monitored via the Internet", "ans_b": "B. A set of guidelines for working DX during contests using Internet access"}, "T1E07": {"question": "When the control operator is not the station licensee, who is responsible for the proper operation of the station?", "ans_a": "A. All licensed amateurs who are present at the operation", "ans_d": "D. The control operator and the station licensee are equally responsible", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Only the control operator", "ans_b": "B. Only the station licensee"}, "T8B08": {"question": "What is meant by the statement that a satellite is operating in mode U/V?", "ans_a": "A. The satellite uplink is in the 15 meter band and the downlink is in the 10 meter band", "ans_d": "D. The satellite frequencies are usually variable", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. The satellite operates using ultraviolet frequencies", "ans_b": "B. The satellite uplink is in the 70 cm band and the downlink is in the 2 meter band"}, "T7D12": {"question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring high voltages with a voltmeter?", "ans_a": "A. Ensure that the voltmeter has very low impedance", "ans_d": "D. Ensure that the voltmeter is set to the correct frequency", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Ensure that the circuit is grounded through the voltmeter", "ans_b": "B. Ensure that the voltmeter and leads are rated for use at the voltages to be measured"}, "T5B05": {"question": "Which of the following is equivalent to 500 milliwatts?", "ans_a": "A. 0.02 watts", "ans_d": "D. 50 watts", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 5 watts", "ans_b": "B. 0.5 watts"}, "T6C03": {"question": "What is component 2 in figure T1?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Connector", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Indicator lamp", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T8B10": {"question": "What do the initials LEO tell you about an amateur satellite?", "ans_a": "A. The satellite battery is in Low Energy Operation mode", "ans_d": "D. The satellite uses Light Emitting Optics", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The satellite is in a Low Earth Orbit", "ans_b": "B. The satellite is performing a Lunar Ejection Orbit maneuver"}, "T9B08": {"question": "Why should coax connectors exposed to the weather be sealed against water intrusion?", "ans_a": "A. To prevent an increase in feed line loss", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. To keep the jacket from becoming loose", "ans_b": "B. To prevent interference to telephones"}, "T4A02": {"question": "How might a computer be used as part of an amateur radio station?", "ans_a": "A. For logging contacts and contact information", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. For generating and decoding digital signals", "ans_b": "B. For sending and/or receiving CW"}, "T7D11": {"question": "Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring circuit resistance with an ohmmeter?", "ans_a": "A. Ensure that the applied voltages are correct", "ans_d": "D. Ensure that the circuit is operating at the correct frequency", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Ensure that the circuit is grounded", "ans_b": "B. Ensure that the circuit is not powered"}, "T1E02": {"question": "Who may a station licensee designate to be the control operator of an amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. Any U.S. citizen or registered alien", "ans_d": "D. Only a person for whom an amateur operator/primary station license grant appears in the FCC database or who is authorized for alien reciprocal operation", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Any person over the age of 18", "ans_b": "B. Any family member of the station licensee"}, "T1B08": {"question": "Which of the following is a result of the fact that the amateur service is secondary in some portions of the 70 cm band?", "ans_a": "A. U.S. amateurs may find non-amateur stations in the bands, and must avoid interfering with them", "ans_d": "D. Digital transmissions are not permitted on 70 cm", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. International communications are not permitted on 70 cm", "ans_b": "B. U.S. amateurs must give foreign amateur stations priority in those portions"}, "T8A08": {"question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a single sideband voice signal?", "ans_a": "A. 1 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 15 kHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 6 kHz", "ans_b": "B. 3 kHz"}, "T7A01": {"question": "Which term describes the ability of a receiver to detect the presence of a signal?", "ans_a": "A.\u00a0Linearity", "ans_d": "D. Total Harmonic Distortion", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Selectivity", "ans_b": "B.\u00a0Sensitivity"}, "T6B03": {"question": "Which of these components can be used as an electronic switch or amplifier?", "ans_a": "A. Oscillator", "ans_d": "D. Voltmeter", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Transistor", "ans_b": "B. Potentiometer"}, "T4B12": {"question": "What is the function of automatic gain control or AGC?", "ans_a": "A. To keep received audio relatively constant", "ans_d": "D. An asymmetric goniometer control used for antenna matching ", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. To eliminate RF on the station cabling", "ans_b": "B. To protect an antenna from lightning"}, "T8C10": {"question": "How do you select a specific IRLP node when using a portable transceiver?", "ans_a": "A. Choose a specific CTCSS tone", "ans_d": "D. Use the keypad to transmit the IRLP node ID", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Access the repeater autopatch", "ans_b": "B. Choose the correct DSC tone"}, "T5A08": {"question": "Which of the following is a good electrical insulator?", "ans_a": "A. Copper", "ans_d": "D. Mercury", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. Aluminum", "ans_b": "B. Glass"}, "T3C06": {"question": "What mode is responsible for allowing over-the-horizon VHF and UHF communications to ranges of approximately 300 miles on a regular basis?", "ans_a": "A. Tropospheric scatter", "ans_d": "D. Faraday rotation", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. F2 layer refraction", "ans_b": "B. D layer refraction"}, "T9A11": {"question": "What is meant by the gain of an antenna?", "ans_a": "A. The additional power that is added to the transmitter power", "ans_d": "D. The increase in impedance on receive or transmit compared to a reference antenna", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The increase in signal strength in a specified direction when compared to a reference antenna", "ans_b": "B. The additional power that is lost in the antenna when transmitting on a higher frequency"}, "T3C10": {"question": "What is the radio horizon?", "ans_a": "A. The distance over which two stations can communicate by direct path", "ans_d": "D. The shortest distance between two points on the Earth's surface", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. The farthest point you can see when standing at the base of your antenna tower", "ans_b": "B. The distance from the ground to a horizontally mounted antenna"}, "T1E04": {"question": "What determines the transmitting privileges of an amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. The frequency authorized by the frequency coordinator", "ans_d": "D. The class of operator license held by the control operator", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The highest class of operator license held by anyone on the premises", "ans_b": "B. The class of operator license held by the station licensee"}, "T1D11": {"question": "When may an amateur station transmit without identifying?", "ans_a": "A. When the transmissions are of a brief nature to make station adjustments", "ans_d": "D. When transmitting signals to control a model craft", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. When the transmitted power level is below 1 watt", "ans_b": "B. When the transmissions are unmodulated"}, "T8B03": {"question": "Which of the following are provided by satellite tracking programs?", "ans_a": "A. Maps showing the real-time position of the satellite track over the earth", "ans_d": "D. All of these answers are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. The apparent frequency of the satellite transmission, including effects of Doppler shift", "ans_b": "B. The time, azimuth, and elevation of the start, maximum altitude, and end of a pass"}, "T0B09": {"question": "Why should you avoid attaching an antenna to a utility pole?", "ans_a": "A. The antenna will not work properly because of induced voltages", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. The antenna could contact high-voltage power wires", "ans_b": "B. The utility company will charge you an extra monthly fee"}, "T8C09": {"question": "How might you obtain a list of active nodes that use VoIP?", "ans_a": "A. From the FCC Rulebook", "ans_d": "D. From the local repeater frequency coordinator", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. From a repeater directory", "ans_b": "B. From your local emergency coordinator"}, "T8D02": {"question": "What does the term \u201cAPRS\u201d mean?", "ans_a": "A. Automatic Packet Reporting System", "ans_d": "D. Advanced Polar Radio System", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Auto Planning Radio Set-up", "ans_b": "B. Associated Public Radio Station"}, "T5B07": {"question": "If a frequency readout calibrated in megahertz shows a reading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show if it were calibrated in kilohertz? ", "ans_a": "A. 0.003525 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 3,525,000 kHz", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 3525 kHz", "ans_b": "B. 35.25 kHz"}, "T2C12": {"question": "What is the Amateur Radio Emergency Service (ARES)?", "ans_a": "A. Licensed amateurs who have voluntarily registered their qualifications and equipment for communications duty in the public service", "ans_d": "D. A training program that certifies amateur operators for membership in the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. A training program that provides licensing courses for those interested in obtaining an amateur license to use during emergencies", "ans_b": "B. Licensed amateurs who are members of the military and who voluntarily agreed to provide message handling services in the case of an emergency"}, "T0B07": {"question": "Which of the following is an important safety rule to remember when using a crank-up tower?", "ans_a": "A. This type of tower must never be painted", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. This type of tower must never be climbed unless it is in the fully retracted position", "ans_b": "B. This type of tower must never be grounded"}, "T6C12": {"question": "What do the symbols on an electrical circuit schematic diagram represent?", "ans_a": "A. Electrical components", "ans_d": "D. Traffic nodes", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Digital codes", "ans_b": "B. Logic states"}, "T2C03": {"question": "What should be done to insure that voice message traffic containing proper names and unusual words are copied correctly by the receiving station?", "ans_a": "A. The entire message should be repeated at least four times", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Such words and terms should be spelled out using a standard phonetic alphabet", "ans_b": "B. Such messages must be limited to no more than 10 words"}, "T9B07": {"question": "Which of the following is true of PL-259 type coax connectors?", "ans_a": "A. They are preferred for microwave operation", "ans_d": "D. They are a bayonet type connector", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. They are commonly used at HF frequencies", "ans_b": "B. They are water tight"}, "T1F03": {"question": "When is an amateur station required to transmit its assigned call sign?", "ans_a": "A. At the beginning of each contact, and every 10 minutes thereafter", "ans_d": "D. At least every 10 minutes during and at the end of a communication", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. At least every 15 minutes during and at the end of a communication", "ans_b": "B. At least once during each transmission "}, "T5D02": {"question": "What formula is used to calculate voltage in a circuit?", "ans_a": "A. Voltage (E) equals current (I) multiplied by resistance (R)", "ans_d": "D. Voltage (E) equals current (I) minus resistance (R)", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Voltage (E) equals current (I) added to resistance (R)", "ans_b": "B. Voltage (E) equals current (I) divided by resistance (R)"}, "T3B08": {"question": "What are the frequency limits of the VHF spectrum?", "ans_a": "A. 30 to 300 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 300 to 3000 MHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 300 to 3000 kHz", "ans_b": "B. 30 to 300 MHz"}, "T6C02": {"question": "What is component 1 in figure T1?", "ans_a": "A. Resistor", "ans_d": "D. Connector", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Battery", "ans_b": "B. Transistor"}, "T4A09": {"question": "Which of the following could you use to cure distorted audio caused by RF current flowing on the shield of a microphone cable?", "ans_a": "A. Band-pass filter", "ans_d": "D. Ferrite choke", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Preamplifier", "ans_b": "B. Low-pass filter"}, "T7B06": {"question": "Which of the following actions should you take if a neighbor tells you that your station\u2019s transmissions are interfering with their radio or TV reception?", "ans_a": "A. Make sure that your station is functioning properly and that it does not cause interference to your own radio or television when it is tuned to the same channel ", "ans_d": "D. Install a harmonic doubler on the output of your transmitter and tune it until the interference is eliminated", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Tell them that your license gives you the right to transmit and nothing can be done to reduce the interference", "ans_b": "B. Immediately turn off your transmitter and contact the nearest FCC office for assistance"}, "T8A11": {"question": "What is the approximate maximum bandwidth required to transmit a CW signal?", "ans_a": "A. 2.4 kHz", "ans_d": "D. 15 kHz", "correct_ans": "b", "ans_c": "C. 1000 Hz", "ans_b": "B. 150 Hz"}, "T0B02": {"question": "What is a good precaution to observe before climbing an antenna tower?", "ans_a": "A. Make sure that you wear a grounded wrist strap", "ans_d": "D. All of the these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. Put on a climbing harness and safety glasses", "ans_b": "B. Remove all tower grounding connections"}, "T6D05": {"question": "What type of circuit controls the amount of voltage from a power supply?", "ans_a": "A. Regulator", "ans_d": "D. Phase inverter", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. Filter", "ans_b": "B. Oscillator"}, "T4B10": {"question": "Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter bandwidth to select in order to minimize noise and interference for CW reception?", "ans_a": "A. 500 Hz", "ans_d": "D. 5000 Hz", "correct_ans": "a", "ans_c": "C. 2400 Hz", "ans_b": "B. 1000 Hz"}, "T4A12": {"question": "What could be happening if another operator reports a variable high-pitched whine on the audio from your mobile transmitter?", "ans_a": "A. Your microphone is picking up noise from an open window", "ans_d": "D. Noise on the vehicle\u2019s electrical system is being transmitted along with your speech audio", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. You need to adjust your squelch control", "ans_b": "B. You have the volume on your receiver set too high"}, "T8D10": {"question": "Which of the following can be used to transmit CW in the amateur bands?", "ans_a": "A. Straight Key", "ans_d": "D. All of these choices are correct", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. Computer Keyboard", "ans_b": "B. Electronic Keyer"}, "T0C03": {"question": "What is the maximum power level that an amateur radio station may use at VHF frequencies before an RF exposure evaluation is required?", "ans_a": "A. 1500 watts PEP transmitter output", "ans_d": "D. 50 watts PEP reflected power", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. 50 watts PEP at the antenna", "ans_b": "B. 1 watt forward power"}, "T2C01": {"question": "When do the FCC rules NOT apply to the operation of an amateur station?", "ans_a": "A. When operating a RACES station", "ans_d": "D. Never, FCC rules always apply", "correct_ans": "d", "ans_c": "C. When operating under special ARES rules", "ans_b": "B. When operating under special FEMA rules"}, "T3C01": {"question": "Why are direct (not via a repeater) UHF signals rarely heard from stations outside your local coverage area?", "ans_a": "A. They are too weak to go very far", "ans_d": "D. They collide with trees and shrubbery and fade out", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. UHF signals are usually not reflected by the ionosphere", "ans_b": "B. FCC regulations prohibit them from going more than 50 miles"}, "T0B05": {"question": "What is the purpose of a gin pole?", "ans_a": "A. To temporarily replace guy wires", "ans_d": "D. To provide a temporary ground", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. To lift tower sections or antennas", "ans_b": "B. To be used in place of a safety harness"}, "T1A07": {"question": "What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telemetry?", "ans_a": "A. An information bulletin issued by the FCC", "ans_d": "D. An information bulletin from a VEC", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A one-way transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument", "ans_b": "B. A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance"}, "T9A13": {"question": "Why are VHF or UHF mobile antennas often mounted in the center of the vehicle roof?", "ans_a": "A. Roof mounts have the lowest possible SWR of any mounting configuration", "ans_d": "D. Roof mounted antennas are always the easiest to install", "correct_ans": "c", "ans_c": "C. A roof mounted antenna normally provides the most uniform radiation pattern ", "ans_b": "B. Only roof mounting can guarantee a vertically polarized signal"}}